Wukong and Bajie looked all around.
But the Tang Monk was gone.
"That tiger ate our master," said Bajie. He shrugged.
"I guess we don't have to protect him anymore. Good-bye, Wukong!"
The pig started to walk away.
But Wukong grabbed him.
"You're not leaving!" said the monkey.
"We have to save our master.
That tiger said he works for a demon, the great king Yellow Wind.
The king's cave must be nearby."
The tiger entered his master's cave.
The Tang Monk was slumped over the tiger's shoulder.
The great king Yellow Wind was sitting on his throne.
"Great king!" cried the tiger. "I found the Tang Monk!"
The demon king looked surprised and happy.
"I have heard that anyone who eats the Tang Monk will live forever.
Was the monk alone?"
"He had two companions," said the tiger.
"One is a pig.
The other is a monkey."
Yellow Wind trembled. "A monkey?" he said.
"He must be Sun Wukong—the monkey who caused all that trouble in Heaven!"
"Maybe," said the tiger. "But don't worry.
I distracted them with a fake tiger skin.
They'll never find us."
The tiger patted his stomach and looked at the Tang Monk.
"I'll tell the other demons to start a fire and prepare some spices."
Yellow Wind held up his hand.
"Sun Wukong is powerful.
He and that pig might come looking for the monk.
They'll be angry if they find out we ate him.
Let's wait until they leave the area.
Then we'll be able to enjoy our meal."
A small demon ran into the throne room.
"Great king!" cried the demon.
"There are two strangers outside—a monkey and a pig.
They said to hand over the Tang Monk.
If we don't, they'll destroy our entire mountain!"
"Oh no," moaned Yellow Wind. "This is bad!"
"Don't worry, King," said the tiger.
"I will get rid of them."
The tiger walked out of the throne room.
The small demon followed him.
Outside the cave there was some yelling and then a crashing sound.
A moment later the small demon ran back in.
"Great king, disaster!" he cried.
"The tiger is dead!
The pig killed him with his rake!"
"What?" cried Yellow Wind.
He stood up and grabbed a trident.
He puffed out his chest and stomped out of the cave.
He saw Wukong.
"So you're the monkey who caused all the trouble in Heaven," said Yellow Wind.
"Hand over the Tang Monk!" demanded Wukong.
"I didn't know you were so small," said Yellow Wind.
"Hit me on the head," said the monkey.
"I'll grow bigger."
The demon king hesitated.
"Go ahead!" said Wukong.
Yellow Wind knocked the monkey on the head.
Instantly Wukong grew tall.
"Now I'll hit you!" cried Wukong.
He swung his iron bar.
Crash! The demon king blocked the bar with his trident.
Clang! The two fought up and down the side of the mountain.
"I'll use some magic," thought the monkey.
He grabbed a handful of hair and blew on it.
Dozens of little Wukongs ran toward the demon king.
Yellow Wind laughed. "I know a magic trick too!"
He looked down and blew three times.
The sky grew dark.
A powerful yellow wind whipped across the mountain.
Trees snapped and rocks tumbled.
Wukong, Bajie, and all the little Wukongs tumbled down the mountain.
They landed at the bottom in a cloud of dust.
The demon king went back into his cave and slammed the door shut.