The two priests pushed the Tang Monk toward the enormous frying pan.
"Stop!" cried Wukong.
[g@The priests stopped.
The Great Immortal looked around.@g]
Wukong appeared and landed on the floor.
"You came back!" cried the Tang Monk.
"I was here the whole time," said the monkey.
[g@He gave Bajie a nasty look.
"I didn't escape without you."@g]
Wukong turned to the Great Immortal.
"Please don't harm the Tang Monk," he said.
[g@"I will fix your ginseng tree.
But I need to get help."@g]
[g@"He's lying!" said Bajie.
"He doesn't know how to fix the tree!"@g]
[g@"Be quiet, Bajie!" said Wukong.
"I'm not lying!"@g]
The Great Immortal thought for a moment.
"Okay, Wukong. I will give you until the [n@end of the day to fix my ginseng tree.
If you can't, the Tang Monk goes into the frying pan."
The monk shook with fear.
"Don't worry, Master," said the monkey.
[g@"I will find help.
I'll be back as soon as I can."@g]
Wukong shot out of the abbey and was gone.
Bajie shook his head. "We're doomed."
Wukong soared through the air until he came to Mount Potalaka.
Guanyin was meditating in her pagoda.
"Bodhisattva!" cried the monkey. "I need your help!
A Daoist named the Great Immortal is going to fry the Tang Monk.
I have until the end of the day to fix his ginseng tree."
"What happened to the tree?" asked Guanyin.
She gave the monkey a suspicious look.
"I, um, knocked it down," said Wukong.
"That was a terrible thing to do, Wukong," said Guanyin.
"The Great Immortal's ginseng tree is older than Heaven and Earth.
It was a rare treasure."
The monkey shrugged. "I was angry."
"You must learn to control your anger," said Guanyin.
[g@The bodhisattva stood up.
She went to a shelf and grabbed a vase.@g]
"This vase is filled with magic dew," she said.
"It can bring spirit plants, such as the ginseng tree, back to life."
A short while later, Wukong and Guanyin arrived at the abbey.
Guanyin told Wukong, Bajie, and Wujing to stand the tree back up.
Guanyin rose into the air and poured the dew over the ginseng tree.
As the dew droplets rolled over the branches, light sparkled.
The tree's color came back, and new leaves and fruit grew.
Soon the tree looked just as it had the day before.
To thank everyone, the Great Immortal decided to host a feast.
"I would like to share some ginseng fruit with everyone here," he said.
Everyone went back into the abbey.
The two priests brought in trays of ginseng fruits.
"Mmm," said Bajie. "This fruit tastes wonderful if you eat it slowly."
[g@He looked at Wukong.
"Sorry I didn't believe you earlier."@g]
[g@"Don't worry about it," said the monkey.
He took a bite of his fruit.@g]
The Tang Monk looked nervously at his fruit.
"It's safe to eat," Guanyin assured him.
[g@The monk took a bite and smiled.
He looked at the ginseng fruit again.@g]
"It doesn't look like a baby anymore," he said.
The next morning the travelers headed west along the road.
Weeks went by as they continued their journey.
They walked through rain and sunshine, heat and cold.
Up ahead, an evil spirit named Lady Whitebone sat by the side of the road.
She had been waiting by the road for years.
On this day she sniffed the air and smiled.
"The Tang Monk is finally approaching.
I will eat him up, and I will live forever!"