Wujing watched as the fake Wujing fed the horse some hay.
"I don't know how you made fake versions of us, [n@Wukong," said the purple spirit.
"But you won't get the True Scriptures without the real Tang Monk."
Wukong folded his arms. "Oh yes, I will."
Wujing leaped into the air and flew south.
"I'll tell the bodhisattva what Wukong is doing," he thought.
"She can stop him."
When Wujing arrived at Mount Potalaka, he was even more shocked.
Wukong was meditating in the bodhisattva's garden.
"Wukong!" cried Wujing. "How did you get here so fast?"
"What are you talking about?" asked the monkey.
[g@Guanyin came out of her pagoda.
"Wujing, what are you doing here?"@g]
[g@The purple spirit bowed.
"Bodhisattva, I must speak with you.@g]
Wukong has made fake versions of me, Bajie, and the Tang Monk.
He's planning to make the journey without us."
"What!" shouted Wukong.
Wujing glanced at the monkey.
"I just saw him on the Fruit and Flower Mountain.
I don't know how he got here before me."
"You're lying!" yelled Wukong.
Guanyin smiled. "You're mistaken, Wujing.
Wukong has been here the whole time."
Wujing was surprised. "He has?"
Guanyin nodded.
Wukong made a fist.
[g@"Someone is pretending to be me!
And he's living on my mountain!@g]
[g@I'm going there right now.
I'm going to destroy him!"@g]
"I'll go with you," said Wujing.
Wukong and Wujing soon arrived on the Fruit and Flower Mountain.
The monkey's eyes burned with anger when he saw the fake Wukong.
"Who are you?" demanded Wukong.
"Who are [i@you?@i]" asked the fake Wukong.
"I am Sun Wukong, king of the Fruit and Flower Mountain!"
"No," said the other monkey.
"[i@I@i] am Sun Wukong, king of the Fruit and Flower Mountain!"
Furious, Wukong pulled out his iron bar.
The fake Wukong pulled out his iron bar.
Wukong attacked, and so did the fake Wukong. [i@Clang!@i]
The ground shook as the iron bars crashed into each other.
The two monkeys fought with fury.
Wujing watched as one Wukong struck the other. [i@Crack!@i]
The other Wukong blocked the bar and swung back. [i@Bam!@i]
"Wujing, help me!" cried one Wukong.
Wujing raised his spear and was about to enter the fight.
[g@The other Wukong shouted.
"No, Wujing! Help [i@me@i]!"@g]
[g@Wujing looked from one Wukong to the other.
"Who is the real Wukong?"@g]
"I am!" shouted one Wukong as he struck at the other.
"No!" shouted the other Wukong, blocking the first one's attack. "[i@I@i] am!"
"Don't listen to him!" cried one monkey.
"Don't listen to [i@him@i]!" cried the other.
[g@Wujing stamped his foot.
"Stop fighting!" he shouted.@g]
[g@Instantly both monkeys stopped fighting.
They looked at the purple spirit.@g]
"I don't know which one of you is the real Wukong," said Wujing.
[g@"Go to Mount Potalaka.
Guanyin will be able to tell who is who.@g]
I will return to the Tang Monk to tell him what's going on."
The two Wukongs glanced at each other.
"That's a good idea," said one of them.
"Guanyin will easily see that I am the real Wukong."
"It [i@is@i] a good idea," the other agreed.
"Guanyin will easily see that [i@I@i] am the real Wukong."
Soon the two Wukongs stood before Guanyin.
She looked carefully at each one.
"I can't tell which one of you is the real Wukong," she said.
[g@One Wukong took a deep breath.
"Use the Tight Headband spell.@g]
The spell will work only with my headband—the real headband."
[g@"Yes!" said the other one.
"Use the Tight Headband spell!@g]
The spell will only work with [i@my@i] headband."