Bajie didn't know Guanyin was really Red Boy in disguise.
"The Tang Monk is in trouble," said the pig to the fake Guanyin.
"A demon named Red Boy is planning to eat him.
Can you help us?"
"Of course," said the fake Guanyin.
"I know Red Boy.
He's very nice.
I doubt he'll harm the Tang Monk.
Let's go to Red Boy's cave and talk to him."
Bajie and the fake Guanyin flew to Red Boy's cave.
Bajie went in first.
Red Boy returned to his normal appearance and then sneaked up behind Bajie.
He threw a sack over the pig.
"Hey, what's going on?" shouted Bajie.
"I'm not Guanyin, you fool!"
The demon laughed.
"I'm Red Boy!
And now you're trapped!"
The demon locked Bajie in a room.
"Why isn't Bajie back yet?" asked Wujing.
Wukong frowned. "He probably stopped to take a nap.
That pig is so lazy."
Wujing nodded. "Yes, he's very lazy.
What should we do now?"
"I'm going to sneak into Red Boy's cave," said Wukong.
"I want to make sure the Tang Monk is still alive.
Then I'll go to Guanyin myself."
The monkey turned himself into a bee and flew up the mountain.
He slipped through the cave door and flew down a long tunnel.
Soon he heard the Tang Monk crying.
"Master is scared," thought Wukong.
"But at least he's still alive."
The monkey then heard a shout.
It was Bajie. "You filthy demon!
How dare you make yourself look like Guanyin and fool me!"
"Aha!" thought Wukong. "Bajie didn't take a nap after all.
I must go to the real Guanyin right away."
The monkey flew out of the cave and told Wujing what he'd just learned.
Then he jumped onto a cloud and headed south.
He found Guanyin in her pagoda.
"Wukong, why are you here?" asked Guanyin.
"We have a problem, Bodhisattva," said the monkey.
"The Tang Monk was caught by a demon named Red Boy.
The demon makes magic fire that water can't put out.
Bajie was on his way here to ask for your help.
But the demon made himself look like you and tricked the pig."
Guanyin's face burned with anger.
"How dare that demon make himself look like me!"
The bodhisattva grabbed a vase and stormed outside.
She threw the vase down into the ocean, where it sank beneath the waves.
Wukong gasped. "That vase was a Buddhist treasure!
Why did you throw it away?"
Guanyin didn't answer.
A minute later the water rumbled.
The vase reappeared.
It was atop the shell of a giant turtle.
The turtle came onto the shore and bowed its head.
"Go down and get the vase, Wukong," said Guanyin.
The monkey ran down the mountain and tried to pick up the vase.
"Grr!" Wukong grunted and used all of his strength.
But no matter how hard he tried, he couldn't lift the vase at all.
"Bodhisattva!" he called. "I don't understand.
It's just a small vase, but I can't lift it!"
Guanyin came down the mountain.
"That vase just traveled around the world, through all the oceans and rivers.
It now holds an ocean's worth of water—magic water.
The water will put out Red Boy's fire."
Guanyin picked up the vase with one hand.
She held up her other hand, and several swords appeared.
She waved them, and they turned into a large lotus platform.
"I have what I need now," said Guanyin. "Let's go."