For over a month, the travelers stayed at Squire Kou's house.
Every time they tried to leave, the squire begged them to stay longer.
Finally, one morning during breakfast, the Tang Monk insisted on leaving.
"We'll never fetch the True Scriptures if we stay here."
"Please don't leave," said Squire Kou.
"You are very important monks.
Having you as guests is a good deed."
"I'd like to stay here," said Bajie.
He took a bite of a peach.
"No. Master's right," said Wukong.
"We must continue our journey."
Lady Kou grew angry.
"You monks are ungrateful!
We have fed you and taken care of you.
Yet you can't wait to leave!"
"We are very grateful," said the Tang Monk.
"But we cannot stay any longer."
After breakfast Wujing got the horse from Squire Kou's stable.
Bajie gathered the bags.
The Tang Monk thanked Squire and Lady Kou, and the travelers headed west.
"They are ungrateful," muttered Lady Kou.
The next morning Lady Kou ran into the town's courthouse.
Tears filled her eyes.
"I must speak with the judge!" she cried.
The judge rushed to her.
"Lady Kou! What's wrong?"
"Robbers broke into our house last night," said Lady Kou breathlessly.
"They stole many valuable items and two of our horses.
Squire Kou tried to stop them, but the robbers . . .
They . . . killed my husband!"
Lady Kou burst into tears.
The judge gasped.
"Oh no! Did you see the robbers?"
Lady Kou sniffed.
"Yes, and I know who they are."
"Who are they?" asked the judge.
Lady Kou gritted her teeth.
"The Tang Monk and his companions!"
The judge turned to a soldier.
"Gather some soldiers and arrest the Tang Monk and his companions!"
"I'm glad we're headed west again,"
said the Tang Monk as the travelers walked.
"I'm eager to reach the Western Paradise."
Wujing nodded.
"We were delayed at Squire Kou's house for too long."
Bajie snorted.
"We should have stayed longer."
Suddenly a group of men stepped onto the road.
They carried swords and axes.
Their horses carried several large bundles.
"Give us your money!" shouted one man.
Wukong pulled out his iron bar.
"Wukong," said the Tang Monk.
"Remember, you must not harm people."
Wukong smiled.
"I'm just going to talk to them, Master."
He turned to the man who had shouted.
"We have no money."
"No money, huh?" said the man.
"Well then, we're going to beat up all of you."
Wukong laughed.
"You don't realize who I am.
I'm Sun Wukong, the Monkey King!"
"I don't care who you are," said the man.
"We're dangerous robbers!
Last night we robbed a very wealthy squire."
The Tang Monk raised his eyebrows. "A squire?"
Wukong quickly recited a spell, which froze the robbers.
Wujing rushed to the horses and opened one of the bundles.
Inside were dishes, jewels, and other valuable items.
Wujing gasped.
"These items belong to Squire Kou!
So do the horses!"
The Tang Monk bit his lip.
"Squire Kou is a good man.
We must return his belongings."
Everyone agreed.
Wukong recited another spell, and the robbers became unfrozen.
The monkey grew large, and fire burned in his eyes.
"Get out of here!" he thundered.
"And never steal again!"
The robbers screamed and ran away.
The travelers headed back toward town with the squire's horses.
Soon they saw a group of soldiers on horseback.
"Those soldiers are riding toward us," said Wujing.
"I wonder what they want," said the Tang Monk.
One of the soldiers pointed a sword at the travelers.
"Stop, thieves! You're all under arrest!"