The demon general looked at Wukong, who was still in disguise.
"The Tang Monk is heading toward our mountain?" the general asked.
"Yes," said Wukong.
"That is great news," said a demon captain.
"Unfortunately there's also some bad news."
Wukong pretended to look worried.
[g@"The Tang Monk has three companions.
One is a big purple fellow.@g]
Another is a pig who appears to be quite lazy."
[g@The general narrowed his eyes at Wukong.
"And the third companion?"@g]
"The third companion is a monkey," said Wukong.
"I believe he is Sun Wukong."
"I was afraid that monkey was traveling with [n@the monk," the general grumbled.
"What does Sun Wukong look like?"
"He's huge." Wukong pretended to shiver.
"He has fiery red eyes and sharp fangs."
"Oh dear," said a captain.
"There's no need to worry about some silly monkey," said the colonel.
[g@"I don't care what he did five hundred years ago.
We have a powerful army."@g]
"I heard the monkey talking," said Wukong.
"He said he [i@hopes@i] there's an entire demon army on this mountain."
[g@"What?" The general looked confused.
"He hopes there's an army?"@g]
Wukong nodded. "He said destroying demons is good exercise.
He has a magic iron bar.
He can make it big enough to crush our entire army with one strike.
But he doesn't plan to do that."
A captain gulped. "What [i@does@i] he plan to do?"
"He plans to crush one demon at a time," said Wukong.
"That way he'll get more exercise."
The demons' faces went pale.
"This is bad news," said the general.
The other demons nodded in agreement.
[g@"You can all stick around if you want to," said Wukong.
"But I'm leaving."@g]
A captain looked surprised.
[g@"What about eating the Tang Monk?
Don't you want to live forever?"@g]
[g@Wukong shook his head.
"I heard our three leaders talking privately.@g]
They don't plan to share the Tang Monk with us.
They're going to eat him themselves."
The officers grew angry.
"That's not fair!" said the colonel.
"It's terrible!" said a captain.
The general bit his lip.
"If our leaders won't share the Tang Monk with us, [n@they can catch him themselves.
Let's gather the troops and leave this place."
Soon Wukong could see the demon army marching away in the valley below.
The monkey smiled.
[g@"I got rid of the army.
Now I'll deal with the three demon leaders."@g]
[g@Still in disguise, Wukong entered the cave.
He came to a large room.@g]
Three huge demons—a lion, an elephant, and a raptor—sat on thrones.
"The Tang Monk is heading toward the mountain," Wukong announced.
[g@"Excellent," said the lion.
"Tell the troops to capture him."@g]
"The troops left," said Wukong.
"What!" shouted the raptor. "Why?"
"The Tang Monk is traveling with Sun Wukong," said the monkey.
"The troops were afraid of the monkey."
"So it's true that Sun Wukong is with the monk," said the elephant.
[g@"That monkey is powerful.
We should leave the Tang Monk alone."@g]
[g@"Nonsense!" said the lion.
"We don't need an army to fight a monkey.@g]
We'll capture the Tang Monk ourselves."
"You're crazy!" said the elephant.
"Sun Wukong defeated Heaven's entire army!"
"Don't call me crazy!" shouted the lion.
"Don't shout at me!" shouted the elephant.
"I'll shout at anyone I want to!" shouted the lion.
As the two demons argued, Wukong began to laugh.
Soon he was laughing hard.
The demons stopped arguing and stared at him.
The monkey looked down and saw that his disguise was gone.
He gulped. "Uh-oh!"