"That woman was a demon!" cried Wukong.
"And she kidnapped the Tang Monk!"
He leaped into the air, and Bajie and Wujing followed.
In the distance the monkey saw a dark cloud speeding toward a mountain.
"That must be her," said Wukong.
"Quickly!" said Wujing. "We must catch her!"
They raced after the cloud, which disappeared when it reached the mountain.
They soon arrived at the mountain and found a cave.
Its door was closed.
Wukong pounded on the cave door.
"Open up!" he yelled.
The door flew open, and the woman came out.
"Who are you?" demanded the woman.
"Why are you pounding on my door?"
"Release our master!" shouted Wukong, ignoring her questions.
The woman laughed.
"Don't tell me what to do!"
The monkey attacked.
The woman spun around fast, blocking his iron bar and striking back with fury.
"You shouldn't have come here!" she shouted as she fought.
"Even Buddha is afraid of me!"
Bajie tried to hit her with his rake but missed.
The woman was now spinning faster and faster.
"She's faster than a tornado!" cried the pig.
Wukong leaped at the woman.
Suddenly he felt a stabbing pain.
"Ahh!" cried the monkey, grabbing his head.
"It hurts! It hurts!"
He ran down the mountain.
Bajie and Wujing stared after Wukong in shock.
The woman went back into her cave.
"What happened to Wukong?" asked the pig.
"Nothing hurts him except for the Tight Headband spell."
"I don't know," said Wujing, scratching his head.
They went down the mountain and found the monkey crouching by a stream.
He was still holding his head.
"Are you all right?" asked Wujing.
"That woman stabbed me in the head," moaned Wukong.
"The pain is horrible!"
Bajie snorted.
"You're always bragging about how tough you are.
Now you're crying about getting stabbed in the head?"
"It hurts!" shouted the monkey.
Wujing moved closer.
"Let me see where she stabbed you."
Wukong lowered his hands.
There was no injury.
Bajie laughed. "He's fine.
He just wants us to feel bad for him."
The monkey glared at the pig.
"I'm telling you, it hurts!"
He took a deep breath.
"The pain is going away now though.
Let's go back up there and fight her again."
The three companions returned to the cave.
"Wukong, you stand back," said Bajie, laughing.
"I don't want you getting hurt again."
Wukong clenched his teeth.
The pig hit the door with his rake. Smash!
The door exploded.
The woman ran outside.
"You smashed my door!" she shouted.
"Release our master!" shouted the pig.
"Or we'll smash your entire mountain!"
The woman spun around, faster and faster.
Bajie and Wujing tried to strike her with their weapons.
But the woman was too fast.
Wukong raised his iron bar, waiting for a good moment to strike.
Suddenly Bajie cried out, "Ahh!"
He covered his nose and ran back down the mountain.
The woman spun toward Wukong and Wujing.
They turned and ran back down the mountain.
Bajie was huddled on the ground, tears streaming from his eyes.
"It hurts so badly!"
Wukong laughed.
"Don't laugh at me!" cried Bajie.
"She stabbed my nose!"
"You deserved it!" said the monkey.
"You didn't believe me when I got hurt."
"Stop arguing," said Wujing.
"We still have to save the Tang Monk."
"You're right," said Wukong. "Let's go back up there."
A voice called out, "Wait!"
It was Guanyin.
The bodhisattva was walking toward the group.
"Beware of that scorpion spirit!"