"I hope we reach the Western Paradise soon," [n@said the Tang Monk one morning.
Wukong and his companions were eating breakfast.
The monkey laughed. "The journey will take many years, Master!
And you must face many challenges along the way.
Buddha doesn't give the True Scriptures to just anyone.
You must prove you're worthy by surviving a long and difficult journey."
The monk sighed.
[g@Bajie put down his bowl.
"I'm tired of this journey!" he cried.@g]
"My legs hurt. And we never have enough food."
[g@"Stop thinking about food, Bajie," said Wukong.
"We're Buddhist monks now.@g]
We should think only about reaching the Western Paradise."
The pig sighed.
After he washed the bowls, the three companions headed down the road.
They soon reached a river.
The water splashed, and a purple monster leaped from the waves.
"Master, stay back!" shouted Wukong.
He pulled out his iron bar and blocked the monster's spear. [i@Clang!@i]
Bajie lunged at the monster, swinging his rake.
The monster dived back into the river.
"Bajie, my powers aren't strong underwater," said Wukong.
"Dive in, and get him to chase you out of the river.
Then I'll surprise him."
"Okay," said the pig.
"Let's wait until he comes all the way up on shore though.
Then I'll block his path so he can't go back in the river."
Bajie dived into the water. Wukong waited.
A moment later the pig was back with the monster following.
The monkey swung his iron bar—and missed.
The monster dived back underwater.
"You didn't wait until he was on shore," said Bajie.
"You're too impatient!"
Wukong shrugged and laughed.
[g@"Let's yell at the monster.
Maybe he'll come back."@g]
Wukong and Bajie yelled at the river for more than an hour.
But the monster did not come back.
Finally the monkey sighed.
"We can't cross this river with the monster in there.
I'll ask Guanyin for help."
Wukong went to Mount Potalaka and told Guanyin about the monster.
[g@"His name is Sha Wujing," said Guanyin.
"He was waiting for you.@g]
He's going to help the Tang Monk reach the Western Paradise."
"I didn't know that!" cried Wukong.
Guanyin went back to the river with Wukong.
"Sha Wujing!" she called. "The Tang Monk is here!"
The monster jumped out of the river and bowed.
[g@"I'm sorry, Bodhisattva," he said.
"I didn't know he'd arrived."@g]
"These two are his companions," said Guanyin.
She waved her hand toward Wukong and Bajie.
[g@Wujing looked surprised.
"They attacked me!"@g]
"You attacked us first!" shouted Bajie.
"Stop arguing," said Guanyin.
"Wujing, you will help the Tang Monk reach the West."
"Yes, Bodhisattva," said Wujing.
Guanyin disappeared, and Wujing joined the group.
He led the horse while the Tang Monk rode.
"I was being punished for breaking a glass in Heaven," said Wujing one day.
"When we reach the Western Paradise, I will be forgiven."
"Bajie and I were punished for crimes in Heaven too," said Wukong.
[g@"So was the horse.
Did you know the horse is really a dragon?"@g]
[g@Wujing looked doubtful.
"This horse is too slow to be a dragon."@g]
"Oh, really?" said the monkey. "Watch this!"
[g@He struck the horse.
The horse shot down the road as fast as lightning.@g]
Its reins were ripped from Wujing's hand.
"Ahh!" cried the Tang Monk.
When the horse finally stopped, the Tang Monk was in a dark forest.
[g@He gasped in fear.
The forest was filled with wolves, bears, and tigers!@g]