Bajie was in the cave when the door opened.
Two small demons entered, dragging Wujing and the Tang Monk.
"What happened?" cried Bajie after the demons left.
"A demon attacked us," said Wujing.
"I tried to fight him, but he was too powerful."
"I'm worried," said the Tang Monk.
"We don't know what happened to Wukong."
In another room inside the cave, Golden Horn talked to some smaller demons.
They all laughed when Golden Horn told them [n@Wukong was trapped under three mountains.
"Let's celebrate!" said one demon.
[g@"Not yet," said Golden Horn.
"I'm afraid Sun Wukong might escape."@g]
He handed a gourd to one of the demons.
"Take this magic gourd to the monkey.
Say his name, and he will be sucked into the gourd.
After an hour he will turn into liquid."
"Yes, Master," said the small demon.
"Grr!" Wukong pushed as hard as he could.
But the mountains were too heavy.
"How will I ever get out of this?" thought the monkey.
He was about to push again when the mountains rose into the air.
Wukong jumped to his feet and looked around.
A spirit stood nearby.
[g@"Wukong, I am the spirit of these mountains.
Please forgive me.@g]
I tried to stop that demon from taking [n@my mountains, but he was too powerful."
The spirit bowed and then vanished with the mountains.
"I'm lucky that spirit arrived," said Wukong.
[g@"Now I must find my companions.
I wonder where that demon lives."@g]
He spotted a small demon coming down the road.
The demon was carrying a gourd.
Wukong ducked behind a rock before the demon saw him.
"Another demon," thought the monkey.
"He probably knows the one who trapped me under the mountains."
Wukong made himself look like a demon and stepped back onto the road.
"Hello!" he called. "Where are you going?"
"My master sent me to capture Sun Wukong," said the demon.
Wukong laughed. "I know that monkey, and I don't like him at all.
I'll help you capture him."
[g@"Thank you," said the demon.
"But I can catch him myself quite easily."@g]
[g@"Oh, really?" asked Wukong.
"How will you catch him?"@g]
[g@The demon showed Wukong his gourd.
"This gourd is magical.@g]
It can hold a demon or a spirit.
I just have to say 'Sun Wukong,' and he'll be sucked into it.
After an hour he'll turn into liquid."
Wukong laughed. "I have a better gourd."
He quickly plucked a hair and turned it into a gourd.
[g@He showed the gourd to the demon.
"It can hold all of Heaven!"@g]
[g@The demon looked interested.
"I wish I had your gourd."@g]
[g@"Well," said Wukong.
"I might be willing to trade gourds with you."@g]
The demon gave Wukong a suspicious look.
"How do I know you're telling the truth?
[g@Prove that your gourd can hold all of Heaven.
Then we'll trade."@g]
"I'll prove it to you," said Wukong.
The monkey recited a quick spell and left his body standing on the road.
He flew fast up to Heaven.
"I must make it look like Heaven got sucked into this gourd," he thought.
"I'll ask the guard to close the gate and dim the stars.
Then it will look like Heaven's gone."
"Greetings, Wukong," said the guard at the southern gate of Heaven.
"I need to pretend that Heaven has been sucked into a gourd," said Wukong.
"When I say 'Heaven,' close the gate and dim the stars."
The guard frowned. "I can't do that!"