The travelers flew through the sky over the Tang Empire.
Tears of happiness rolled down the Tang Monk's cheeks.
"I see the emperor's palace!"
"I will wait here while you all deliver [n@the True Scriptures," said the guard.
The Tang Monk and his companions went down to Earth and entered the palace.
[g@The emperor's eyes lit up.
"My brother!" He embraced the monk.@g]
"For many years I wondered if I'd ever see you again.
Did you get the True Scriptures?"
"Yes," said the monk.
[g@"But please forgive me.
The journey took much longer than I expected."@g]
"There's no need to apologize," said the emperor.
[g@Then he noticed the monk's companions.
"Who are they?"@g]
Wukong stepped forward.
[g@"I am Sun Wukong, the Monkey King.
I once defeated Heaven's entire army."@g]
"And I am Zhu Bajie," said the pig.
"My name is Sha Wujing," said the purple spirit.
"They protected me during the journey," the monk explained.
"I couldn't have reached the Western Paradise without them."
The emperor bowed to Wukong and the others.
[g@The monkey laughed.
"You don't need to bow.
We were happy to help.@g]
[g@Well, Wujing and I were.
Bajie complained the entire time."@g]
The pig snorted.
There was a huge feast that night.
The emperor asked the monk many questions about the journey.
He listened in amazement to the monk's stories.
"I will build a magnificent pagoda," the emperor declared.
"The True Scriptures will be kept safe inside it."
He put his hand on the monk's shoulder.
"You will always be remembered as the brave monk who traveled to the West.
Because of you, our people won't have to suffer anymore."
After the food was eaten, the emperor asked [n@the monk to read from the scriptures.
[g@The Tang Monk smiled.
"I would be happy to read from them."@g]
The monk sat on a platform, where the scriptures had been placed in baskets.
He unrolled a scroll.
Suddenly light filled the room.
The Tang Monk and his companions rose into the sky.
"We should return to the Thunderclap Monastery," said the guard.
"Buddha is waiting for you."
"Yes, let's go," said the monk.
The travelers were soon bowing before Buddha again.
Other buddhas and bodhisattvas stood behind him.
Buddha addressed the horse first.
"You carried the Tang Monk on the journey and [n@earned forgiveness for your crimes.
You will now be a golden dragon in Heaven."
Light flashed as a large golden dragon soared into the sky.
"Wujing," said Buddha.
"You too have earned forgiveness for your past crimes.
You will now be a golden deity."
[g@Wujing's body turned gold.
The spirit bowed.
"Thank you, Buddha."@g]
"You have earned forgiveness, Bajie," said Buddha.
"You will be Janitor of the Altars—an important deity [n@who looks after Buddhist altars."
Bajie bowed. "Thank you, Buddha."
Buddha next turned to the Tang Monk.
"Because of you, the people in the East will never have to suffer again.
[g@"You made a journey that no other person could make.
You are now a buddha."@g]
Light glowed around the monk, who bowed before Buddha.
"Thank you, Buddha," said the monk.
Finally Buddha turned to the monkey.
[g@"And you, Wukong," he began.
"Your crimes long ago were terrible.@g]
But since then you have used your tremendous powers to do good deeds.
You too are now a buddha."
Wukong bowed. "Thank you, Buddha."
"Hey . . ." The monkey suddenly noticed that his head felt different.
"The headband is gone!"
Buddha smiled. "You don't need it anymore."
Filled with joy, Wukong and the Tang Monk joined [n@the other buddhas and bodhisattvas.
They have been in the Western Paradise ever since.