Look! A penny!
[e@Look! A penny!
That's one cent.
[e@That's one cent.
Oh! A nickel!
[s@Oh! A nickel!
[e@Oh! A nickel!
That's five cents.
[s@That's five cents.
[e@That's five cents.
Cool! A dime!
[s@Cool! A dime!
[e@Cool! A dime!
That's ten cents.
[s@That's ten cents.
[e@That's ten cents.
Ooh! A quarter!
[s@Ooh! A quarter!
[e@Ooh! A quarter!
That's twenty-five cents.
[s@That's twenty-five cents.
[e@That's twenty-five cents.
Wow! A dollar!
[s@Wow! A dollar!
[e@Wow! A dollar!
That's one hundred cents.
[s@That's one hundred cents.
[e@That's one hundred cents.
A penny! A nickel! A dime! A quarter! A dollar!
[s@A penny! A nickel! A dime! A quarter! A dollar!
[e@A penny! A nickel! A dime! A quarter! A dollar!
My piggy bank is full.
Happy Father's Day!
[s@Happy Father's Day!