Wukong led the monks to his companions.
The monks told the Tang Monk everything that they had told Wukong.
"That's terrible," said the Tang Monk.
"We must help you."
"Yes," the monkey agreed.
"I'll deal with the Tiger Immortal in the morning."
The monks knew of an empty building nearby.
They led the travelers there, and everyone went to sleep for the night.
The next morning Wukong woke up early.
Someone was pounding on the door of the building.
A voice boomed, "I am the Tiger Immortal!"
The Tang Monk's eyes popped open.
He and all the other monks trembled with fear.
Wujing and Bajie drew their weapons.
Wukong smiled. "Don't worry, everyone.
I'll deal with this villain."
The monkey went outside.
"Who are you?" demanded the Tiger Immortal.
"I am Sun Wukong," said the monkey.
"And you should be ashamed of yourself!
Just because you're a little powerful, you think you can treat the Buddhist monks badly."
"A little powerful?" The Tiger Immortal looked offended.
"I am very powerful!"
Wukong laughed. "You're not as powerful as I am.
Did you know that the Jade Emperor is afraid of me?
I once defeated his entire army."
The Tiger Immortal puffed out his chest.
"I can summon rain," he said.
"I doubt you can do that."
Wukong snorted. "I can summon rain. It's easy."
"Well then, let's have a contest," said the Tiger Immortal.
"Whoever summons more rain is the winner.
If you win, I'll let you and all the monks go free.
But if I win, you must stay here and be my slaves."
"You're a fool," said Wukong.
"I accept your challenge."
The Tiger Immortal led everyone into town.
In the center of town was a Daoist altar.
A stone tablet, incense sticks, and papers with magic writing were on the altar.
A crowd of people arrived to see what was going on.
"I will go first," announced the Tiger Immortal.
He walked toward the altar.
The Tang Monk shook his head.
"This is terrible," he muttered.
Bajie glanced at him.
"Don't worry, Master.
Wukong will win this contest."
"But what if he doesn't win?" asked the monk.
"We'll all be stuck here, forced to work for the Tiger Immortal.
If that happens, we'll never reach the Western Paradise.
The True Scriptures will never get to the Tang Empire."
The monk buried his face in his hands.
"Bajie is right, Master," said Wujing.
"We have nothing to worry about."
Wukong stood by them, smiling.
From the altar the Tiger Immortal called out, "I will now pray to Heaven for rain!"
The Tiger Immortal lit the incense and then sat down.
He closed his eyes and began to recite a spell.
Next he lit one of the papers on fire.
When that one went out, he lit another paper.
Soon all of the papers were gone.
The Tiger Immortal lifted the stone tablet and then slammed it down. Bam!
There was a gasp from the crowd.
Wukong looked up at the sky, which was becoming dark.
Wind blew and dark clouds moved in. Thunder rumbled.
The Tang Monk trembled. "Oh no!
It's working! It's going to rain!"
Wukong chuckled. "You all wait here.
I'll be right back."
The monkey recited a quick spell and then left his body.
Up in the sky, he found the Old Woman of the Wind fanning the clouds.
The Dragon King of the Eastern Sea was approaching.
Wukong called out, "Stop what you're doing!
Don't make any rain!"