"Cock-a-doodle-doo."
It is morning on Grandpa's farm.
[e@It is morning on Grandpa's farm.
"Cluck, cluck, peep, peep. I'm hungry," said the chicken.
[s@"Cluck, cluck, peep, peep. I'm hungry," said the chicken.
[e@"Cluck, cluck, peep, peep. I'm hungry," said the chicken.
"Baa, baa. I'm hungry," said the sheep.
[s@"Baa, baa. I'm hungry," said the sheep.
[e@"Baa, baa. I'm hungry," said the sheep.
"Quack, quack. I am hungry," said the ducks.
[s@"Quack, quack. I am hungry," said the ducks.
[e@"Quack, quack. I am hungry," said the ducks.
"Neigh, neigh. I am hungry," said the horse.
[s@"Neigh, neigh. I am hungry," said the horse.
[e@"Neigh, neigh. I am hungry," said the horse.
"Moo, moo. I am hungry," said the cow.
[s@"Moo, moo. I am hungry," said the cow.
[e@"Moo, moo. I am hungry," said the cow.
"Oink, oink. I am hungry," said the pig.
[s@"Oink, oink. I am hungry," said the pig.
[e@"Oink, oink. I am hungry," said the pig.
"Bark, bark, bark," said my dog.
[s@"Bark, bark, bark," said my dog.
"Oh, you are hungry too."