"Surprise!"
[e@"Surprise!"
"Are they pencils?" said the teacher.
[s@"Are they pencils?" said the teacher.
"No," said the children.
[e@"No," said the children.
"Are they erasers?" said the teacher.
[e@"Are they erasers?" said the teacher.
"No," said the children.
[e@"No," said the children.
"Are they rulers?" said the teacher.
[s@"Are they rulers?" said the teacher.
[e@"Are they rulers?" said the teacher.
"No," said the children.
[e@"No," said the children.
"Are they scissors?" said the teacher.
[e@"Are they scissors?" said the teacher.
"No," said the children.
[e@"No," said the children.
"Are they colored markers?" said the teacher.
[e@"Are they colored markers?" said the teacher.
"No," said the children.
[e@"No," said the children.
"Are they notebooks?" said the teacher.
[e@"Are they notebooks?" said the teacher.
"No," said the children.
[e@"No," said the children.
"Are they pencil cases?" said the teacher.
[s@"Are they pencil cases?" said the teacher.
[e@"Are they pencil cases?" said the teacher.
"No," said the children.
[e@"No," said the children.
"Are they rubber stamps?" said the teacher.
[e@"Are they rubber stamps?" said the teacher.
"Yes, they are.
Happy birthday, Teacher!"