Guanyin recited the Tight Headband spell.
Both Wukongs fell to the ground, howling in pain.
"Please stop!" they cried.
Guanyin stopped reciting the spell, and the two monkeys stood back up.
The bodhisattva frowned.
"I still don't know which of you is the real Wukong.
[g@You should both go to Heaven.
The real Wukong used to live there.@g]
Maybe the Jade Emperor can tell who is who."
[g@"Good idea," said one Wukong.
He pointed at the other.@g]
"The Jade Emperor will see that this monkey is a fake!"
"I'm not a fake!" cried the other monkey. "You are!"
He tried to strike the other Wukong.
But that one dodged the blow and swung back.
The two monkeys were still fighting when they arrived [n@at the southern gate of Heaven.
[g@The guard narrowed his eyes.
"Wukong? Is that you?"@g]
"Yes, it's me," said both of the Wukongs.
"I must speak with the Jade Emperor," said one monkey.
[g@He pointed at the other monkey.
"He's a fake Wukong!"@g]
"I'm not a fake Wukong!" said the other monkey.
[g@"I'm the real one!
I must speak with the Jade Emperor!"@g]
The guard allowed both Wukongs to enter Heaven.
[i@Crash! Clang! Bang!@i]
Spirits and gods fled as the two Wukongs fought all over Heaven.
The monkeys knocked over statues and trees.
Still fighting, they stormed into the Cloud Palace.
When the Jade Emperor saw them, he was furious.
"What's going on?" he boomed.
"Your Majesty!" said one of the Wukongs.
[g@"Please punish this monkey.
He's pretending to be me."@g]
[g@"Punish [i@him!@i]" cried the other.
"He's pretending to be me!"@g]
"Stand still, both of you," said the Jade Emperor.
"Let me get a good look at you."
The two Wukongs stood still as the Jade Emperor looked carefully at them.
Finally the emperor shrugged.
[g@"You look exactly alike.
I can't tell who is who."@g]
One of the Wukongs swung at the other with his iron bar.
"I'm the real Wukong!"
"No!" The other Wukong blocked the bar and swung back.
"Both of you, leave at once!" thundered the Jade Emperor.
[g@"One Wukong is bad enough.
I don't want two of you around.@g]
You can fight somewhere else!"
The two monkeys kept fighting as they headed out of the palace.
The spirit of the planet Venus followed them.
"Wukong, wait," said the spirit.
Both monkeys stopped to look at him.
"Go to the Land of Darkness," said Venus.
"Maybe the Judge of the Dead can tell you apart."
Soon the two Wukongs were standing before the Judge of the Dead.
[g@The judge shook his head.
"You look exactly alike."@g]
"Check the Directory," said one of the Wukongs.
"Maybe it will have some information about a fake Sun Wukong."
"Yes," said the other Wukong. "Check the Directory."
The judge nodded and opened the Directory.
He turned the pages of the giant book, reading carefully.
Finally he closed it.
"There's no 'Fake Sun Wukong' in the Directory," said the judge.
"I'm sorry. But I have no idea which one of you is the real Wukong."
A spirit was sitting at a nearby desk.
"I believe my pet beast, Curious Ear, can help," said the spirit.
He took a step back, and a small beast crept out from under the desk.
"Curious Ear can tell the true from the false," said the spirit.
The beast stared hard at the two Wukongs.
[g@Finally it spoke.
"I know who the fake Sun Wukong is."@g]