Bajie and Wujing swung their weapons at the demon.
[g@"Ha!" The demon laughed.
"I'm much too powerful for you!"@g]
From inside the cymbals, Wukong heard the fight.
He heard grunts and the sounds of weapons clashing.
The Tang Monk cried, "No!"
Then there was silence.
[g@"What happened out there?" shouted Wukong.
There was no answer.@g]
The monkey punched and kicked the inside of the cymbals for hours.
But the two cymbals would not come apart.
[g@"This is terrible," he said to himself.
"How will I get out of here?"@g]
The monkey was about to strike the cymbals again when he heard a voice.
"Wukong, are you in there?"
"Who is that?" Wukong asked.
"I'm the Gold Dragon," said the voice.
"The Jade Emperor sent me to help you.
I'll wedge my horn between the cymbals and pry them apart."
"Please hurry!" said Wukong.
Slowly the dragon's horn poked through.
But the cymbals were still tightly clasped together.
Wukong groaned. "I can't escape."
"Maybe we can find another way to pry the cymbals apart," said the dragon.
"Actually, I have a different idea," said the monkey.
Wukong turned his iron bar into a drill.
He made a hole in the dragon's horn.
Then he made himself tiny and climbed into the hole.
"Pull your horn out now!" said Wukong.
The dragon pulled and pulled and finally got his horn out.
The monkey jumped out of the hole and returned to his normal size.
[g@"Thank you," said Wukong.
"Now we must free my friends."@g]
[g@"We have to be quiet," said the dragon.
"The demon is sleeping."@g]
[g@Wukong nodded.
Then he turned toward the cymbals and raised his iron bar.@g]
[i@Smash!@i] The cymbals shattered.
"Why did you do that?" cried the dragon.
Wukong shrugged. "I was angry."
[g@The demon stormed into the room.
"Sun Wukong! How did you escape?"@g]
[g@"Who are you?" demanded Wukong.
"How do you know my name?"@g]
"My name is Yellow Brows," said the demon.
"I've been waiting for you and the Tang Monk to pass by my mountain."
Wukong narrowed his eyes. "Why?"
"I'm a Buddhist," said the demon.
"I plan to go to the Western Paradise and get the True Scriptures myself."
"You can't do that!" shouted Wukong.
The monkey and the dragon charged toward the demon.
The demon pulled a cloth from his robe and threw it.
The cloth wrapped around Wukong and the dragon, [n@and then became very small.
Soon they were tied up in a room.
The Tang Monk, Bajie, and Wujing were also in the room.
Their bags were lying in a corner.
"I'm sorry for not believing you, Wukong," said the Tang Monk.
"You suspected this place was dangerous."
"Don't worry about that, Master," said the monkey.
"We must escape as soon as the demon goes back to sleep.
He plans to get the True Scriptures himself."
The group waited for a while.
Finally Wukong made himself tiny and slipped out from his ropes.
He untied his companions and the dragon.
[g@"Let's go," the monkey whispered.
"Bajie, get the bags."@g]
"Everyone, be quiet," the dragon warned.
They tiptoed through the monastery and were soon outside.
[g@Wukong looked at Bajie and frowned.
"Where are the bags?"@g]
[g@The pig moaned.
"I forgot them."@g]
"Master's special robe is in one of those bags!" Wukong sighed.
"Wait here. I'll go back in and get them."
The monkey quietly hurried back to the room and grabbed the bags.
But as he was leaving, he tripped and knocked over a statue. [i@Bang!@i]
From another room Yellow Brows shouted, "What was that?"
Wukong gulped. "Uh-oh."