Bajie took a step back as a dark mist surrounded the people on the road.
When the mist cleared, he saw they were really [n@a monster and several little demons.
The monster grinned at him.
[g@"Yes, you [i@are@i] here for the feast, Pig.
We're going to eat you for lunch!"@g]
"What?" Bajie raised his rake and swung as the monster approached.
The demons rushed toward the pig from all sides.
"That rotten monkey lied to me!" cried Bajie.
He spun around and knocked over two demons with his rake.
[g@The monster threw a punch.
Bajie blocked the punch with his rake.@g]
"Ow!" cried the monster, rubbing his hand.
Bajie kicked a demon sneaking up behind him.
"That monkey is always causing problems!" the pig muttered.
He slammed the rake down on another demon.
[g@"So what if I like to eat?
Did he really have to trick me?"@g]
The monster attacked again.
Bajie thrust his rake toward him, still complaining about Wukong.
"Wukong is small—he doesn't need to eat as much as I do!"
The monster suddenly stopped fighting and looked at Bajie curiously.
"You just said 'Wukong.'
Are you talking about Sun Wukong, the monkey who defeated [n@Heaven's entire army five hundred years ago?"
"Um, yes," said Bajie. "Do you know him?"
"I've heard he's traveling with the Tang Monk," said the monster.
"You must be traveling with the Tang Monk too."
"Why are you interested in the monk?" asked Bajie suspiciously.
The monster licked his lips.
"I've heard that anyone who eats the Tang Monk will live forever."
Panicked, Bajie ran from the demons and back to his companions.
[g@He pointed at Wukong.
"You tricked me!"@g]
[g@The monkey was laughing.
"How was the feast, Bajie?"@g]
[g@"Grr!" Bajie's eyes burned with fury.
He turned to the Tang Monk.@g]
"Wukong told me there was a feast up ahead.
[g@But instead it was a group of demons and a monster.
They tried to eat me!"@g]
The Tang Monk was angry.
"Bajie, I thought you were going to check the mountain!
Instead you went to look for a feast?
[g@You lied to me.
You should be ashamed of yourself!"@g]
[g@Bajie hung his head.
By now Wukong was rolling on the ground, laughing.@g]
"And you, Wukong," snapped the Tang Monk.
"I should recite the Tight Headband spell to punish you!"
[g@Instantly the monkey stopped laughing.
He jumped to his feet.@g]
"Please don't do that!"
"You knew there were demons and a monster ahead," said the monk.
"And you didn't say anything?"
[g@Wujing shook his head.
"You should have said something, Wukong."@g]
"I admit I knew about the demons and the monster," said Wukong.
"But they're not dangerous."
"Not dangerous?" Bajie scoffed.
[g@"They wanted to eat me!
And now they're planning to eat Master!"@g]
"Oh no!" cried the Tang Monk.
[g@Wukong held up his hands.
"Relax, Master. You have nothing to worry about."@g]
"We must capture the Tang Monk," the monster said to the demons.
[g@"But we need a plan.
Sun Wukong is strong.@g]
Did you know that he once defeated Heaven's entire army?"
"Yes, we've heard," said one of the demons.
[g@Another demon hurried over.
"I just spied on the travelers.@g]
The Tang Monk has three spirit companions—Sun Wukong, [n@that pig, and a purple fellow."
"Hmm," said the monster. "That's bad."
"Not really," said the demon.
"I have a plan to lure the spirits away from the monk."
The demon told the monster his plan.
[g@When he was done speaking, the demon folded his arms.
"What do you think?"@g]
[g@A big smile spread across the monster's face.
"I love it!"@g]