"I hope we reach the Western Paradise soon," said the Tang Monk.
"This journey has been very dangerous."
[g@Bajie nodded.
"Those three demons tried to pickle me!"@g]
Everybody laughed, even Bajie.
"Wukong, what happened to those demons?" asked Wujing.
[g@"Buddha took them away," said Wukong.
"I'm sure they were punished."@g]
"Thank you again for saving us," said the Tang Monk.
Wukong waved his hand.
[g@"It was nothing, Master.
Buddha did most of the work."@g]
The group felt a strong wind blow down from the mountains up ahead.
A dark fog filled the sky and then disappeared.
[g@The Tang Monk was nervous.
"Wh-what caused that wind and fog?"@g]
"Relax, Master," said Wukong.
[g@"I'm sure it was something harmless—maybe [n@some small demons.
I'll go check."@g]
The monkey walked up the road and around a bend.
He heard laughter and looked up.
High above the road, a fat monster was sitting on the edge of a cliff.
Several little demons sat next to the monster.
Wukong flew up to get a closer look.
The fat monster appeared to be concentrating.
Suddenly . . . "Braap!" A burp as loud as thunder blew down the mountain.
The demons giggled and laughed.
"That was your best burp yet!" cried one demon.
[g@The monster patted his belly.
"Yes, I'm proud of that one."@g]
"Show us the fog again!" said another demon.
"Coming right up!" said the monster.
He covered one nostril with a finger, closed his eyes, and blew hard.
Dark fog poured out of his other nostril.
The demons clapped and cheered.
[g@The monster smiled and then . . .
"Braap!" More wind blew down the mountain.@g]
[g@There was a roar of laughter.
One demon nearly fell off the cliff.@g]
Wukong shook his head.
"I'm not worried about these demons," he said to himself.
"They're disgusting but not dangerous."
[g@The monkey smiled.
"It does give me an idea though . . ."@g]
Wukong returned to his companions, who were waiting alongside the road.
"Did you see any demons?" asked Wujing.
[g@Wukong shook his head.
"The road is safe."@g]
[g@Then the monkey pulled Bajie aside.
"Bajie," he whispered.@g]
[g@"There's a village up ahead.
The people there are preparing a huge feast.@g]
I saw vegetables, noodles, tofu, steamed buns, [n@and all sorts of delicious food.
I thought maybe you'd like to go before us and start eating."
[g@Bajie licked his lips.
"Thank you for thinking of me, Wukong.@g]
[g@I am rather hungry right now."
The pig turned to the Tang Monk.@g]
"Master, I think I should go ahead and check the mountain too.
I trust Wukong, of course.
But we must protect you, and I'd like to be extra safe."
The Tang Monk smiled.
[g@"I'm impressed, Bajie.
Thank you for doing extra work."@g]
Bajie winked at Wukong and then headed up the road.
"Braap!" The monster burped again, and another wind blew.
Then he blew more fog from one nostril.
The demons laughed hysterically.
Suddenly there was a loud rumbling sound, and everyone was silent.
[g@The monster patted his big belly.
"I'm hungry."@g]
The demons looked at one another.
"I'm hungry too," said one.
"It's probably time for lunch," said another.
The monster stood up.
"Let's go down to the road and find some people to eat!"
The demons cheered and followed the monster down the mountain.
When they got to the road, they made themselves look like people.
The monster chuckled.
"The next time someone comes along this road, it's lunchtime!"
[g@For a few moments, they waited.
Then a large pig came around the bend.@g]
[g@"Hello!" said Bajie, smiling.
"I'm here for the feast!"@g]