Bajie waved his rake at the demon Golden Horn.
"You'll never harm the Tang Monk!" shouted the pig.
"My rake is very powerful!"
Bajie rushed toward Golden Horn.
But the demon was strong.
Bajie was knocked out.
When he woke up, he was tied up in a dark cave.
"Bajie is taking a long time to search the mountain," said the Tang Monk.
"I hope he's okay."
Wukong frowned. "He probably went back to sleep.
I should have followed him again."
"Let's keep walking," said Wujing.
"We'll find Bajie along the way."
"We must stay alert though," said Wukong.
"We still don't know if there are any demons on this mountain."
The group headed up the mountain.
Soon they heard a voice.
"Help me!" cried a man.
"Someone is in trouble," said the Tang Monk.
He and his companions hurried ahead and found an old monk lying near the road.
"Thank goodness!" cried the old monk.
"You must help me."
The Tang Monk got down from his horse.
"Of course we will help you," he said.
"Please stand up."
"I can't," said the old man.
"My leg is injured.
It hurts terribly."
He started to cry.
"How will I ever get back home?"
"Please don't cry," said the Tang Monk.
"We will help you.
How did your leg get hurt?"
"A tiger attacked me," said the old monk.
Wukong looked suspiciously at the man.
"He isn't really a monk," he thought.
"I'm sure he wants to harm Master.
But I can't tell Master that—he won't believe me."
"Wukong," said the Tang Monk.
"Please carry this poor monk down the mountain."
Wukong walked over and picked up the old monk.
"Ouch!" cried the monk.
"Be careful, Wukong," said the Tang Monk.
"His leg is hurt badly."
The group continued along the road.
Wukong carried the injured monk.
He walked slowly, letting the Tang Monk and Wujing go ahead.
"I know you're really a demon," the monkey whispered.
"And I know you want to eat the Tang Monk."
"I don't know what you're talking about," said the monk.
"I'm just a simple monk who was attacked by a tiger."
Wukong laughed. "Do you know who I am?
I am Sun Wukong.
Heaven's entire army couldn't defeat me.
You're going to wish you'd never tried to harm the Tang Monk."
As Wukong talked, he felt a heavy weight pressing down on him.
He glanced up and realized an entire mountain was balanced on top of his head.
The monkey laughed again.
"So you're going to use magic tricks to trap me under a mountain?
Well, let me tell you—Buddha himself once trapped me under a mountain.
And I was able to lift it."
Wukong felt more weight.
Now he had two mountains on top of him.
He walked more slowly.
"This still isn't enough weight to stop me," he said.
"Now that the Tang Monk isn't around, I should clobber you with my iron bar."
Suddenly the old monk vanished.
A third mountain appeared on top of the first two.
Wukong's knees buckled, and all three mountains crashed down on top of him.
The monkey was trapped.
The old monk appeared again.
There was a flash of light as he changed back into his demon form.
Golden Horn laughed with delight.
"Wukong was the most powerful of these travelers.
It will be easy to defeat Wujing.
Tonight I will dine on the Tang Monk!"