Wukong leaped into the air.
His three companions and the horse fell into the water with a splash.
Bajie climbed back out, coughing.
Wujing came up next, pulling the horse behind him.
"Where's the Tang Monk?" cried Wukong.
Below the ice the Tang Monk struggled as the [n@demon carried him deep underwater.
[g@The demon laughed.
"You all fell for my trick!@g]
I froze the river and waited for you to cross it.
Once you were above me, I cracked the ice open.
As soon as your friends leave, I will eat you and live forever!"
They arrived at a palace.
A sign over the door read "Residence of the River Turtle."
The demon went inside and locked the monk in a stone box.
Up on the ice, Wukong paced back and forth.
"The ice didn't crack by accident," said the monkey.
"I'm sure it was the demon.
[g@The demon probably caused this strange cold weather too."
He made a fist.@g]
[g@"I can't believe we fell for his trick!
We must save the Tang Monk!"@g]
Wukong stopped pacing and looked at his companions.
"My powers aren't very strong underwater.
You two must go down there and get the demon to come back up.
I'll surprise him."
Wujing and Bajie nodded and dived into the river.
They soon spotted a palace.
Wujing read the sign over the door:
[g@"'Residence of the River Turtle.'
I wonder if the demon is in here."@g]
[g@Bajie knocked on the door.
"Open up!" he shouted.@g]
[g@The door opened, and the demon stepped out.
He was holding a large hammer.@g]
"What do you want?" he asked.
"Did you kidnap our master?" asked Wujing.
[g@"Yes," said the demon. "And I plan to eat him.
Now go away!"@g]
The demon tried to close the door, but Wujing [n@stopped the door with his spear.
[g@The demon moved toward him.
Bajie's rake came crashing down.@g]
[i@Clang!@i] The demon blocked the rake with his hammer.
Fish and other creatures fled as the three spirits fought.
After a few minutes, Bajie pretended to be scared.
He swam upward, and Wujing soon followed.
"Cowards!" called the demon, swimming after them toward the surface.
The demon jumped out of the water and onto the ice.
[g@Wukong was waiting for him.
The monkey swung his iron bar.@g]
[g@The demon ducked.
[i@Crack!@i] The bar hit the ice.@g]
[g@The demon swung his hammer.
[i@Bam!@i] More cracks formed in the ice.@g]
[i@Clang! Boom! Crash!@i]
Weapons clashed as the spirits fought on the breaking ice.
The demon hit Bajie's legs.
[g@"Whoa!" cried the pig.
He slid across the ice and slammed into Wujing.@g]
"Oof!" The purple spirit slipped and fell.
"Ha!" The demon laughed and dived back under the ice.
Bajie and Wujing stood back up.
"The demon escaped," said the pig.
"We must stop him before he eats the Tang Monk," said Wukong.
"Go back down there and try to lead him up here again."
Wujing and Bajie dived into the river.
When they reached the palace, they found a huge [n@pile of rocks blocking the door.
[g@Bajie struck the rocks with his rake.
The rake bounced off the rock pile.@g]
[g@The rocks didn't move at all.
Wujing stabbed at the rocks with his spear.@g]
Again, the rocks didn't move.
"What kind of rocks are these?" cried the pig.
"Maybe they're held in place with magic," said Wujing.
They returned to the surface of the river and told Wukong about the rocks.
[g@The monkey sighed.
"We need Guanyin's help."@g]