Wukong stared at the river.
"I should have stopped Master from getting in that canoe.
But whenever I warn him about someone, he doesn't believe me."
Wujing nodded. "I'll find out where that man took our friends."
[g@The purple spirit dived into the river.
He soon came to a palace.@g]
A sign on the gate read "Home of the Black River God."
Wujing tapped on the door with his spear. "Open up!"
The door opened, and a lizard peeked out.
"What do you want?" asked the lizard.
"I'm looking for my companions," said Wujing.
[g@"One is a monk, and the other is a pig.
They were kidnapped by a man."@g]
"They were kidnapped by me," said the lizard.
"You?" said Wujing.
[g@"Yes." The lizard smiled.
"I plan to eat the Tang Monk and live forever!"@g]
Wujing struck at the lizard with his spear.
The lizard spun around, blocking the spear with his tail.
The force nearly knocked Wujing over.
Right away the lizard was on top of him.
[g@"Get off me!" shouted Wujing.
He shoved the lizard.@g]
[g@The lizard attacked again.
Wujing swung his spear and then swam upward.@g]
He splashed out of the river and landed next to Wukong.
"There's a lizard demon down there," said Wujing, breathing heavily.
"He's very powerful."
Wukong was about to respond when he noticed someone nearby.
The man from the canoe was walking toward them.
[g@The monkey pulled out his iron bar.
"How dare you kidnap our friends!"@g]
[g@The man fell to his knees, shaking.
"It wasn't me!" he cried.@g]
[g@"It was a lizard demon.
I'm the Black River God, and this is my river.@g]
But that lizard pretended he was me!"
Wukong put the iron bar back in his ear.
[g@"I believe you," he said.
"Do you know who the lizard is?"@g]
[g@"I don't," said the river god.
He looked even more frightened now.@g]
"But his uncle is the mighty Dragon King of the Eastern Sea."
Wukong laughed. "That dragon is a friend of mine.
[g@He's also a bit scared of me.
I'll go have a talk with him."@g]
A moment later the monkey was at the Dragon King's palace.
[g@"Hello again, Wukong," said the dragon, smiling.
"What can I do for you?"@g]
"Why did you let your nephew take over the Black [n@River?" demanded the monkey.
[g@The dragon's smile faded.
"What are you talking about?"@g]
"Your nephew—a lizard demon—took over the Black River," said Wukong.
"And now he's planning to eat the Tang Monk."
[g@"Oh dear," said the dragon. "I had no idea.
I'll take care of it."@g]
Wukong and the dragon flew back to the Black River.
The Dragon King shouted, "Nephew! Come out of that river at once!"
The lizard leaped from the river.
"Uncle!" he said. "It's nice of you to visit."
"I'm not here to visit!" yelled the dragon.
[g@"I'm here to take you to the Jade Emperor.
You will be punished."@g]
The lizard gulped.
His head hanging low, he followed his uncle up into the sky.
With a splash, the river god appeared from the water.
The Tang Monk and Bajie were with him.
"Thank you, Wukong," said the god.
"You're welcome," said the monkey.
"But we still need to cross your river."
[g@"That's easy," said the river god.
He held up his hand.@g]
Instantly the river stopped flowing, and the water formed walls.
The travelers walked across the muddy riverbed and continued west.