After the Tang Monk sent Wukong away, he and the others continued west.
Later that day they stopped to rest.
[g@Bajie sat down in the grass next to the road.
He let out a great big yawn.@g]
"Bajie," said the Tang Monk.
[g@"Why don't you go find us some food?
Wujing and I will wait here."@g]
[g@The pig moaned. "Ugh! I just sat down!"
He got back up.@g]
[g@"This journey is too difficult," he said.
Then he wandered off.@g]
[g@After a few minutes of walking, Bajie looked around.
He was all alone.@g]
"I'm too tired to look for food," he said to himself.
"But if I go back now, Master will be angry."
[g@He yawned. "I'll take a nap.
When I wake up, I'll go back to Master.@g]
I'll tell him I searched everywhere but couldn't find any food."
[g@The pig lay down behind some bushes.
Soon he was snoring loudly.@g]
An hour later the Tang Monk and Wujing were still waiting by the road.
"What is taking Bajie so long?" asked the monk.
Wujing looked annoyed.
"He probably found food and is now eating it all himself.
I'll go and look for him."
Wujing got up and headed down the road.
"Mmm," said a voice suddenly. "Yummy noodles!"
Wujing frowned. "That's Bajie.
He [i@did@i] find food, and he's not sharing it with us!"
Meanwhile the Tang Monk became bored.
[g@He stood up to stretch his legs.
He looked around.@g]
"This is a beautiful forest," he said to himself.
"I'll take a short walk."
The monk walked quietly through the woods, [n@admiring flowers and plants as he went.
He went deeper and deeper into the forest.
Then, in the midst of all the trees, he saw a pagoda.
"This is a strange place for a pagoda," he thought.
"Maybe we can all stay here tonight."
The Tang Monk went to the door of the pagoda and opened it.
He gasped. A monster was sleeping inside!
The monster had a purple beard and long, sharp fangs.
The Tang Monk tried to walk away, but the monster woke up.
[g@"Who's there?" called the monster.
He stood up.@g]
The Tang Monk turned around, shaking with fear.
"Sorry to wake you," he said. "I, uh . . ."
The monster came closer and smiled.
[g@"You're a monk," he said.
He licked his lips.@g]
"Y-yes," said the Tang Monk. "I'm from the T-Tang Empire. I . . ."
[g@The monster's eyes lit up.
"You're the Tang Monk!"@g]
Meanwhile Wujing stomped toward Bajie's voice.
He peered behind some bushes and saw the pig fast asleep.
[g@"May I have more tofu?" asked Bajie.
He was talking in his sleep.@g]
[g@"Yes, please cook lots more.
I will eat it all."@g]
Wujing kicked the pig. "Wake up!"
Bajie jumped to his feet, wiping drool from the side of his mouth.
"How dare you sleep while we wait for you?" said Wujing.
"Now let's go back to Master."
[g@The pig sighed.
With his head hung low, he followed Wujing back to the road.@g]
But when they got there, the Tang Monk was gone.
"Maybe he went for a walk," said Wujing.
He and Bajie wandered through the woods, looking for the monk.
Soon they saw the pagoda.
They knocked on the door, and the monster answered.
"Who are you?" asked the monster.
[g@Wujing told the monster who they were.
"We're looking for a monk."@g]
The monster laughed.
[g@"I have a monk here.
I'm going to eat him for dinner!"@g]