The travelers walked up the Spirit Mountain.
The mountain's slopes were covered in pine trees, bamboo, and flowers.
Birds sang, and small animals ran by.
The Tang Monk stopped walking and turned to his companions.
"I want to thank you all," said the monk.
"You have helped me to reach the Western Paradise.
You saved me from demons countless times.
I couldn't have gotten here without you."
Wukong laughed.
"You don't need to thank us, Master.
We all helped each other.
You helped me to be good.
Now I will earn forgiveness for the evil things I did long ago."
Wujing nodded.
"And I will earn forgiveness for breaking that glass in Heaven."
"I will earn forgiveness for causing trouble in Heaven too," added Bajie.
He waved a hand toward the horse.
"And remember—that horse is really a dragon.
He accidentally set fire to his father's palace.
He too will earn forgiveness."
Wukong smiled.
"See, Master? We are all thankful."
They continued up the mountain and were soon surrounded by clouds.
Bright light shone from the Thunderclap Monastery above.
The travelers arrived at an enormous gate, where two guards stood.
Beyond the gate the Thunderclap Monastery's towers and arches sparkled with bright light.
"Greetings," said the monk to the guards.
"I am the Tang Monk, and I'm here to receive the True Scriptures from Buddha."
"You may enter," said one of the guards.
The Tang Monk and his companions reached a large hall.
Buddha sat at the opposite end of the hall.
Other buddhas and bodhisattvas stood behind him.
Guanyin was standing next to Buddha and smiling.
The travelers bowed.
"Congratulations," said Buddha.
"You have all traveled far and faced many challenges.
You have done well."
Wukong's heart swelled.
He wiped a tear from his eye.
"Thank you," said the Tang Monk.
"It was an honor to make the journey."
Servants brought a meal to the travelers.
When the travelers were done eating, a guard led them to a large room filled with magical light and mist.
Wooden chests lined the walls.
Inside the chests were countless scrolls.
"Marvelous," the Tang Monk murmured.
"The True Scriptures are written on these scrolls," said the guard.
He picked out three scrolls and handed them to the Tang Monk.
Speechless, the monk gazed at the scrolls.
Then he handed them to Wujing and Bajie.
The two spirits carefully wrapped the scrolls and placed them in a bag.
Again the travelers bowed before Buddha.
"Take the True Scriptures back to the Tang Empire," said Buddha.
"Ugh, another long journey," Bajie murmured.
"Stop complaining, Bajie," whispered Wukong.
Bajie whispered back.
"Don't tell me what to do."
"Both of you, stop arguing!" whispered Wujing.
Buddha was still talking.
"The scriptures will teach the people there to be good and to treat each other kindly.
But take good care of the scriptures.
They are extremely valuable.
Once you have delivered them, you shall come back here to receive your rewards."
"Don't worry, Buddha," said Wukong.
"We will protect the scriptures with our lives."
A guard offered to carry the travelers to the Tang Empire.
"Thank you," said the Tang Monk.
"What a relief!" said Bajie.
The guard recited a spell and then flew out of the monastery with the travelers.
Buddha turned to Guanyin.
"The Tang Monk and his companions have done well."
Guanyin nodded.
"Wukong especially has learned a lot during the journey.
He isn't violent anymore.
I believe he is now a good Buddhist."
Just then a messenger ran into the hall.
"Bodhisattva!" he cried. "We have a problem!"