Wukong gasped as his companions began to look ill.
The Tang Monk's head bobbed forward, and his teacup dropped from his hand.
[g@And then—[i@thump!@i]
The monk toppled to the floor.@g]
A moment later Wujing and Bajie passed out too.
"Evil villain!" Wukong jumped to his feet and pulled out his iron bar.
The priest backed away.
Just then a door burst open, and the three women ran into the room.
"You again?" cried the monkey.
He leaped out of the way as the women shot webs at him.
He jumped up, did a flip in the air, and landed directly behind the women.
Furiously, he slammed his iron bar down.
[i@Wham!@i] There was a puff of smoke.
When it cleared, a dead spider lay where one of the women had been.
The other two women stared in horror.
"He destroyed our sister!" cried one.
"He's a monster!" cried the other.
Wukong charged toward them.
He knocked flying webs out of his way and then . . . [i@Crack! Bam!@i]
[g@Both women were gone.
In their places lay dead spiders.@g]
"Those spider spirits were my dear friends!" cried the priest.
[g@His eyes burned with fury.
"You will regret destroying them."@g]
The priest opened his robe, revealing a body covered in eyes.
Suddenly, blinding light shot from the many eyes.
"Aargh! The light is too bright!" cried the monkey.
He covered his own eyes and ran all over the room.
But he couldn't escape the blinding light.
Finally he slammed his iron bar into the abbey's stone floor.
[g@A huge hole opened up.
The monkey jumped in and turned into a mole.@g]
Using his claws, he tunneled until he was sure he was far from the abbey.
When Wukong popped up out of the ground, he turned back into himself.
Bright light was shining from the abbey.
Even from far away, the light burned the monkey's eyes.
Wukong turned away.
[g@"What will I do?
I have no way to save my friends.@g]
That priest's light is too powerful."
[g@He sobbed and sobbed until he heard a voice say,
"Don't cry, Wukong."@g]
[g@The monkey looked up.
A tall woman was standing over him.@g]
"I am the bodhisattva Pralambra," said the woman.
"That priest is a centipede spirit, called the Demon Lord of Many Eyes.
I am the only one who can defeat him."
Pralambra pulled a small needle from her sleeve.
Turning, she threw the needle into the beams of light.
[i@Crack!@i] The sound thundered in the sky, and the beams of light vanished.
Wukong and Pralambra returned to the abbey.
[g@The priest lay shaking on the floor.
All of his eyes were squeezed shut.@g]
Pralambra pointed her finger at the priest, [n@and he turned into a giant centipede.
Pralambra took a bottle out of her sleeve.
"Here, Wukong," said the bodhisattva.
"These pills will cure your companions.
I will take the centipede with me to be punished."
Wukong bowed. "Thank you, Bodhisattva."
The journey continued, and many weeks went by.
"The journey has been easy lately," said the Tang Monk one day.
Bajie snorted.
"That's true," said Wujing.
"It's been weeks since any demons tried to eat Master."
"The Western Paradise is still far away," Wukong warned the others.
"We'll face many more dangers before we get there."
The Tang Monk smiled.
[g@"Relax, Wukong, and enjoy the beautiful day.
There is no danger here."@g]
[g@Just then a man appeared up ahead.
He was waving his arms frantically.@g]
"Don't come this way!" shouted the man.
"There's danger ahead—great danger!"