The travelers laid the soaked scrolls on some rocks.
"The sun will dry them out," said Wukong.
The Tang Monk moaned.
"What if they're ruined?"
He sat down and put his head in his hands.
"I wish I'd remembered to ask Buddha the turtle's question!"
Bajie snorted.
"Who cares if you forgot the turtle's question?
That turtle had no right to dump us in the water!"
"Dumping us in the water was rude," Wujing agreed.
Bajie sighed.
"The journey back east is becoming just as difficult as the journey west."
"Hello!" cried a voice.
The travelers turned and saw a man hurrying toward them.
"Chen," said the Tang Monk.
He grasped the man's hands.
"It's good to see you again."
"It's good to see all of you." Chen smiled.
"Did you reach the Western Paradise?"
"Yes," said the Tang Monk.
"It was magnificent!
The land is filled with beauty."
Chen noticed the scrolls lying on the rocks, and his eyes went wide.
"Are those the True Scriptures?" he whispered.
"Yes," said the monk.
"But as you can see, they got wet."
"A giant turtle dumped us in the river," added Bajie with a sigh.
"Please come with me," said Chen.
"You can dry the True Scriptures by my fire.
Everyone in the village will be excited to see the travelers who met Buddha."
Wujing started gathering the wet scriptures.
"I'll help you," said Bajie.
The pig grabbed a scroll and pulled.
But it was stuck to a rock.
Rip! The corner of the scroll tore off.
The Tang Monk gasped. "Oh no!"
Bajie stared in horror at the torn scroll.
Wukong smiled. "Don't worry, Master."
The monkey gently picked the rest of the scroll off the rock.
"The scroll is fine."
"But it's ripped!" cried the monk.
Bajie hung his head.
"Tell me something, Master," said Wukong.
"Are you perfect?"
The monk gave Wukong a confused look.
"Of course not."
"Am I perfect?" asked the monkey.
The Tang Monk shook his head.
"How about Bajie?" Wukong smirked.
"We all know he's not perfect."
The pig snorted.
"Nothing on Earth or in Heaven is perfect," said Wukong.
"So why should the True Scriptures be any different?
They'll teach the people of the East how to be good and avoid suffering.
They will also teach the people that nothing needs to be perfect."
The travelers finished gathering the scrolls and followed Chen back to the village.
People came out of their homes to see the travelers.
"Welcome back!" called a woman.
"It's wonderful to see you all again!" shouted an old man.
Soon a crowd was following the Tang Monk and his companions to Chen's house.
That evening the villagers held a big feast.
Later that night Wukong and the Tang Monk sat, talking.
"We must leave soon," said the monk.
"The villagers will want to see the True Scriptures.
They'll become jealous that we have them."
"I agree," said Wukong.
He remembered the priest who'd tried to kill the Tang Monk and steal the robe.
"Let's sneak away now, while the villagers are asleep," said Wukong.
The monk and the monkey woke up Bajie and Wujing.
The group sneaked out of Chen's house and headed east.
It was dark, but the light from the full moon lit up the road.
Suddenly the guard from the Thunderclap Monastery appeared.
"Congratulations!" said the guard.
"You have faced one hundred challenges."
"Whew." The monk sighed with relief.
"I will become a buddha at last."
The guard recited a spell.
Once again the travelers flew toward the East.