Wukong struggled to free himself from the golden rope.
The gourd fell from his robe.
"My magic gourd!" said Golden Horn, picking it up.
He dragged Wukong to a dark room in the cave and locked him in.
Right away Wukong made himself tiny and escaped.
He flew down a tunnel and squeezed through the cave's main door.
Once he was outside, he returned to his normal size.
He banged on the cave door.
"Open up right now!"
The door flew open and Golden Horn appeared.
"Sun Wukong!" shouted the demon.
"How did you escape?"
"I'm not Sun Wukong," the monkey lied.
"But you look just like him," said Golden Horn.
"Yes, I do," said Wukong.
"Sun Wukong is my twin brother.
My name is Sun Kongwu."
"Why are you here, Sun Kongwu?" asked Golden Horn.
"I know you captured my brother," said Wukong.
"Set him free."
Golden Horn laughed.
"I'm not going to do that!"
"Oh, that's too bad," said Wukong, pretending to feel bad.
"I was hoping to solve this problem without violence."
He took the iron bar out of his ear.
Golden Horn had been holding the gourd behind his back the whole time.
He quickly held it up and shouted, "Sun Kongwu!"
Shloomp! Wukong was sucked into the gourd.
Golden Horn put a cap on the gourd and went back into his cave.
Inside the gourd Wukong stamped his foot.
"How will I get out of here?
I know I won't turn into liquid because I'm going to live forever.
But I still have to save my friends."
He tapped his chin.
"I have an idea."
He plucked a hair and made it look almost exactly like himself.
There was just one difference.
The fake Wukong had no legs.
Next Wukong made a hair look like a puddle.
He placed the fake Wukong on the puddle.
Now it looked as if the fake Wukong's legs had turned into liquid.
Then the monkey made himself very, very tiny.
Wukong went near the opening of the gourd and shouted, "Oh no! My legs turned into liquid!"
The gourd shot out light as Golden Horn removed the cap.
The tiny Wukong leaped out, unseen.
Golden Horn peered into the gourd and saw the fake Wukong in the puddle.
"Ha-ha! The monkey's legs did turn into liquid.
Soon his entire body will be liquid!"
Golden Horn laughed again and closed the gourd.
He put the gourd down and started eating.
The real Wukong returned to his normal size and then made himself look like a demon.
He walked over to Golden Horn.
"Hello, sir," said Wukong.
"Are you enjoying your lunch?"
"Yes," said Golden Horn.
Wukong picked up the gourd.
"Is Sun Kongwu still in here?"
"Yes," said Golden Horn.
"He will turn completely into liquid soon.
Stop asking me questions.
I'm trying to eat my lunch."
Golden Horn tilted his head to take a drink.
Wukong slipped the gourd into his robe.
He quickly made a fake gourd with one of his hairs.
He put it on the table and then ran outside.
Wukong changed back into himself and then banged on the cave door again.
Golden Horn threw the door open.
"My name is Kong Sunwu," said Wukong.
"You captured my nephews.
Return them at once!"
Golden Horn held up the fake gourd. "Kong Sun—"
"Wow!" cried Wukong, interrupting the demon.
"I have a gourd that looks just like that!"