Wukong looked at the Dragon King and sighed.
[g@"You're right," said the monkey.
"I did make a promise to Guanyin."@g]
He put down his teacup and stood up.
[g@"Thank you, my friend.
I will visit again soon."@g]
[g@The Dragon King smiled.
"Good luck, Wukong."@g]
The monkey hurried out of the Dragon King's palace.
He found the Tang Monk traveling alongside a stream.
"Master, I have returned," he called.
"I'm glad you're back, Wukong," said the monk. "I'm hungry."
"I'll find a village and beg for some food for you," said the monkey.
"You don't need to do that," said the monk.
[g@"There's rice in the bag.
You can cook that."@g]
[g@The monk got down from the horse.
Wukong opened the bag.@g]
[g@When he looked inside, his eyes opened wide.
He pulled out the headband.@g]
"This headband is marvelous!" said Wukong.
[g@"Oh," said the monk, watching the monkey closely.
"Do you like it?"@g]
"Yes!" said Wukong.
"Try it on," said the monk.
"Really?" asked Wukong.
The monk nodded.
[g@Wukong put the headband on.
He looked at his reflection in the stream.@g]
"I look handsome!" said Wukong. "Thanks for—ahh!"
The monkey grabbed the sides of his head and fell over.
[g@His eyes bulged.
"My head's going to explode!" he cried.@g]
He saw the Tang Monk talking quietly.
"Wh . . . What are you saying?" cried Wukong.
The Tang Monk stopped talking, and the pain stopped.
"The bodhisattva Guanyin taught me a spell," said the monk.
"She gave me the headband to force you to be good."
[g@Wukong pulled at the headband.
But it wouldn't come off.@g]
[g@"It's stuck!" cried the monkey.
He stamped his foot.
"You tricked me!"@g]
[g@"It's for your own good," said the monk.
"You must stop being violent."@g]
Wukong pulled out his iron bar and lunged at the Tang Monk.
The monk recited the Tight Headband spell again.
Wukong fell to the ground and rolled around in pain.
"It hurts! It hurts!" he cried.
"Please stop! I won't try to hurt you again!"
The Tang Monk stopped, and the monkey stood up.
"Now will you cook some rice?" asked the monk.
"I'll get a fire started," said Wukong.
The monkey waited until the Tang Monk had turned his back.
Again he raised the iron bar.
But the Tang Monk saw Wukong's shadow.
"Ahh!" cried Wukong, once again falling to the ground.
The Tang Monk looked furious as he recited the spell.
Wukong's head pounded.
"Please stop!" cried the monkey.
The Tang Monk stopped reciting the spell.
"Don't try to hit me again," said the monk.
"If you do, I'll recite the spell until your head really does explode."
[g@"I'm sorry, Master," said Wukong.
"I'll be good!"@g]
[g@The two traveled for a few more weeks.
They arrived at a wide river.@g]
"How will we cross this river?" asked the monk.
"It's too bad you're not a spirit," said Wukong.
[g@"I can leap over this river.
But I can't take you with me."@g]
"Why not?" asked the Tang Monk.
"You're a human," said the monkey.
"So you must make the journey all by yourself.
[g@I can only protect you.
I can't carry you."@g]
"What will we do then?" asked the monk.
Before Wukong could answer, the water swelled and a dragon leaped from it.
"Look out!" cried the monkey.
He yanked the Tang Monk off the horse as the dragon struck.
With one bite, the dragon swallowed the horse [n@and then slipped back underwater.