The Tang Monk glared at Wukong.
"Bajie says you can bring the king back to life," said the monk.
"Please do so now."
Wukong shot a look at Bajie, who was trying not to laugh.
"Master, use the Tight Headband spell!" said the pig.
"Don't!" cried Wukong. "I'll ask Laozi for help.
He makes pills that can make people live forever.
Maybe he makes pills that can bring people back to life."
[g@Laozi was busy working on a potion.
Steam rose from the bubbling cauldron.@g]
Suddenly Wukong burst into the room. "Hello, Laozi!"
Laozi groaned. "What are you doing here, Wukong?
You're supposed to be helping the Tang Monk reach the Western Paradise."
Wukong walked around the room, looking at all the bottles and equipment.
"I'm still helping the Tang Monk," he said.
"We're helping a king right now though."
He poked a blue bottle filled with liquid.
Laozi looked up from his potion.
[g@"Don't touch anything.
Just tell me why you're here."@g]
"I need pills that will bring someone back to life," said Wukong.
"Give me one thousand of them."
Laozi stopped what he was doing and walked over to Wukong.
"How dare you tell me to give you one thousand pills!" he said.
"Get out of here right now!"
[g@The monkey laughed. "I'm kidding.
I don't really need one thousand pills.@g]
Just give me one hundred, and then I'll leave."
Laozi squeezed his hands into fists.
[g@"I'm not giving you any pills.
Now get out of here!"@g]
Wukong scratched his head, pretending to think.
"Now that I think about it, I don't need one hundred pills.
Just give me ten."
"You are rude and disrespectful!" yelled Laozi. "Get out!"
[g@"I really just need one pill," said Wukong.
"Give me that."@g]
"Get out!" shouted Laozi.
Wukong sighed and then left.
[g@Laozi went back to his potion and stirred.
But then he stopped.@g]
"That monkey will definitely come back [n@and cause trouble," he said to himself.
"I should just give him a pill."
The sage opened a jar and took out a pill.
He went outside and found Wukong waiting for him.
"Hello again," said the monkey.
"I was just trying to decide what sort of trouble I could cause for you."
[g@Laozi frowned, shoving the pill toward Wukong.
"Take this and leave."@g]
Wukong returned to the monastery.
Everyone watched as the monkey put the pill in the king's mouth.
Light sparkled around the king, and then his eyes popped open.
The king sat up and looked at Wukong.
[g@"You . . . saved me," the king said.
"I'm alive again!"@g]
He turned and saw the prince standing nearby. "My son!"
[g@"Father!" said the prince.
He took his father's hands and bowed his head.@g]
[g@"I've missed you.
It's time for you to return to your palace."@g]
The prince led everyone to the palace.
They walked past guards and went into the throne room.
The prince kneeled down before the Daoist.
[g@"Greetings, son," said the Daoist.
"Who are these people?"@g]
[g@The prince stood up.
"This is the Tang Monk.@g]
He is going to the Western Paradise to get scriptures from Buddha.
These three are his companions."
The Daoist looked at a person standing near them.
[g@The person was wearing a hood.
"Who is that man wearing the hood?"@g]
The man pulled the hood back and showed his face.
The Daoist gasped. "The king!"
Wukong pulled out his iron bar and leaped toward the Daoist.
The Daoist snapped his fingers and vanished.