Time passed, and it was soon spring.
The air grew warm, flowers bloomed, and birds swooped from tree to tree.
The road Wukong and the others were traveling began to go up a mountain.
[g@Wukong stopped the group.
"Bajie, go up the road and search the mountain.@g]
There might be a demon up there, and I don't want Master to get hurt."
[g@"Ugh," moaned the pig.
"You make me do all the hard work."@g]
Dragging his feet, he headed up the mountain road.
[g@Wukong turned to the Tang Monk and Wujing.
"I'm going to follow the pig.@g]
I want to make sure he really searches the mountain."
The monkey turned invisible and followed Bajie up the road.
The pig walked for a few minutes.
When he was sure his companions wouldn't hear him, he turned around.
"You dummies!" shouted Bajie.
[g@"You make me do all the hard work!
Well, guess what?@g]
[g@I'm not going to search this mountain.
I'm going to take a nap instead.@g]
And when I come back, I'll lie and say I searched the mountain!"
[g@Bajie found a big log.
He lay down behind it and fell fast asleep.@g]
[g@"This pig is so lazy," thought Wukong.
"I'll teach him a lesson."@g]
The monkey turned himself into a woodpecker and pecked the log.
[i@Tap, tap, tap! Tap, tap, tap!@i]
Bajie rolled over and mumbled.
[g@Wukong pecked again.
[i@Tap, tap, tap! Tap, tap, tap!@i]@g]
[g@The pig sat up.
"Quit tapping, you annoying woodpecker!@g]
[g@I'm trying to sleep!"
He fell asleep again.@g]
[g@Wukong landed on Bajie's head.
[i@Tap, tap, tap! Tap, tap, tap!@i]@g]
"Ouch!" cried the pig, jumping to his feet.
Wukong flew away.
[g@Bajie rubbed his head.
"I can't even take a nap!"@g]
He sighed. "I guess I'll go back down."
When Bajie found his companions, he lied.
"I searched the entire mountain," he said. "It's safe."
"Did you see any demons or monsters?" asked Wukong.
Bajie shook his head.
[g@"How about woodpeckers?" asked the monkey.
"Did you see any of them?"@g]
[g@The pig looked surprised.
"What . . . how did you . . . ?"@g]
"That was me, Bajie!" shouted Wukong.
[g@"You took a nap!
You didn't search the mountain at all!"@g]
Bajie hung his head.
"You should be ashamed of yourself, Bajie," said Wujing.
[g@The Tang Monk frowned.
"Please go back and search the mountain, Bajie."@g]
The pig headed back up the road.
He had walked for a while when he saw a fox.
"I know that's you, Wukong!" he shouted.
[g@He swung his rake.
The fox trotted away.@g]
A robin flew past Bajie's head.
"Get away from me, Wukong!" yelled the pig.
As he waved the rake at the bird, Bajie tripped and fell.
"Wukong!" shouted the pig.
[g@"I know you're here.
You're invisible, and you just tripped me."@g]
He got back up and stood still for a moment.
When he didn't see or hear Wukong, he continued walking.
Every time Bajie saw an animal, he waved his rake and yelled.
[g@The road became very steep.
The pig soon came to a cave.@g]
In front of the cave was a demon.
[g@Bajie held out his rake.
"Tell me who you are!" he demanded.@g]
[g@"My name is Golden Horn," said the demon.
"Who are you?"@g]
"I am Zhu Bajie," said the pig.
"I'm traveling to the Western Paradise with the Tang Monk."
[g@"Oh, the Tang Monk . . ."
A smile curled along the demon's lips.@g]
"I have heard that anyone who eats the Tang Monk will live forever."