For over a day, the wind from the fan carried Wukong.
When he finally landed, he was far from the Iron Immortal's mountain.
Wukong looked around and saw a mountain nearby.
It looked familiar.
"Mount Sumeru!" said Wukong.
"The bodhisattva Lingji lives there.
Maybe he can help me deal with the Iron Immortal.
He was able to stop the great king Yellow Wind's wind magic."
The monkey went to Lingji's pagoda.
The bodhisattva was sitting in his garden.
"Greetings, Bodhisattva," said Wukong.
"Hello, Wukong," said Lingji.
"It's good to see you again.
I was just about to have tea."
Wukong and Lingji sat outside, drinking tea.
The monkey told the bodhisattva everything that had happened with the Iron Immortal.
The bodhisattva handed a small stone to Wukong.
"Keep this magic stone in your pocket.
It will stop the wind from blowing you away."
"Thank you, Bodhisattva," said the monkey.
"Would you like to stay for lunch?" asked Lingji.
"No, thank you," said Wukong.
"I must get back to my companions.
I need to get that fan from the Iron Immortal so we can continue west."
Wukong returned to the Iron Immortal's cave door.
"Open up!" he shouted. "I need your fan!"
The Iron Immortal came out and wrinkled her nose.
"I thought I got rid of you."
She raised her fan.
"I'll just have to wave harder this time!"
The woman waved the fan furiously.
A terrible wind blew past Wukong.
But the monkey didn't move.
The Iron Immortal's eyes burned with anger.
"How did you—"
"The bodhisattva Lingji gave me a magic stone," said Wukong.
"Your fan can't blow me away now."
The monkey pulled out his iron bar.
"Now give me that fan!"
The Iron Immortal shot back into her cave.
Before she could shut the door, Wukong turned into a cricket.
He quickly leaped into the cave.
Silently he followed the Iron Immortal along a tunnel.
When the woman reached a room, she sat down.
She tucked the fan into her robe.
"Wukong is a horrible monkey!" she said to herself.
"He forced my poor baby, Red Boy, to become good.
Then he demanded to borrow my precious fan!"
The Iron Immortal reached for a cup of water.
As she took a drink, Wukong leaped into the cup.
Gulp!
Inside the Iron Immortal's stomach, Wukong changed back into himself.
Boomph! Pow! Boomph! Pow!
The monkey punched and kicked.
The Iron Immortal fell to her knees.
"Ahh! What was in that water?
I feel awful!"
"It was me!" shouted Wukong.
"I'm in your stomach now!
And I won't stop punching and kicking until you give me that fan!"
Boomph! Pow!
"Please stop!" cried the Iron Immortal.
"You can have the fan.
Just don't hurt me anymore!"
Wukong leaped out through the woman's nose and returned to his normal size.
"Give me the fan!" he demanded.
The Iron Immortal climbed back to her feet.
She reached into her robe and pulled out a fan.
"Here, take it. Now leave!"
Wukong found his companions in the village with the old man.
The monkey explained how he'd tricked the Iron Immortal.
"Wonderful!" said the Tang Monk.
"Now we can continue our journey."
They all thanked the old man and then headed west.
They came to the top of a hill and saw the Mountain of Flames.
Fire covered all the land around it.
"Watch this," said Wukong.
The monkey waved the fan hard. Whoosh!
A strong wind blew toward the mountain.
Wukong smiled. "In a moment, we'll—"
Suddenly there was a roar as the flames grew bigger, filling the sky!