"Why won't Wukong help us?" the horse asked Bajie.
The pig sighed.
"He told us not to look for him if we needed help.
Plus I kept telling Master to use the Tight Headband spell.
I'll bet the monkey is really mad at me."
"That doesn't matter now," said the horse.
"You must get Wukong to come back."
Bajie hesitated for a moment and then leaped onto a cloud.
He soared through the sky and soon arrived at the Fruit and Flower Mountain.
He found Wukong sitting beside the big waterfall.
Other monkeys and apes were nearby.
They held swords and spears.
They stared at Bajie silently.
"Hello, Wukong," said the pig. "This is a lovely mountain."
Wukong scowled. "What are you doing here, Bajie?"
The pig looked at the ground.
"The Tang Monk would like you to come back," he mumbled.
"Well, that's too bad," said Wukong, standing up.
"He told me to leave.
I'll never help him again."
"Please come back," said Bajie.
"We all miss you."
"I don't miss you," said Wukong.
"You told Master to use the Tight Headband spell.
I should take out my iron bar and clobber you!"
Bajie forced a laugh.
"I was just joking, Wukong.
I knew you were really just protecting Master."
"It wasn't funny," said Wukong.
"That spell really hurts!"
The pig began to cry.
"Please come back.
The Tang Monk is in danger—big danger.
A monster turned him into a tiger.
And Wujing was captured."
Wukong shrugged.
"Just tell the monster that you're friends with me, the Monkey King.
He'll be scared and leave all of you alone."
"Oh, I did tell him about you," Bajie lied.
"Really?" Wukong leaned closer.
"What did he say?"
Bajie bit his lip.
"He laughed and said that you're a tiny little coward."
Wukong's eyes blazed with fury.
"He will regret saying that! Let's go, Bajie!"
The monster sat in the dining hall, still disguised as a handsome young man.
He was eating a meal with the king and the queen.
A servant came in and handed a note to the young man.
The young man read the note and stood up.
"I'm sorry, Your Majesty, but I must go."
He ran out of the dining hall.
From behind a pillar, the servant watched the man leave.
Light sparkled, and the servant turned into Bajie.
The pig giggled. "The monster is going to be so surprised!"
The young man ran outside and turned back into a monster.
He flew through the air and returned to his pagoda.
He burst through the door in a panic.
Then he saw Princess Hundred Flowers and relaxed.
"Oh, my sweet!" he cried. "I was so scared.
I thought I had lost you forever!"
"Why did you think that?" asked the princess.
The monster sighed. "I got a note.
It said there was a monkey here, and he was trying to destroy my pagoda."
"A monkey was here earlier," said the princess.
"Really?" said the monster.
He looked around.
"He didn't destroy the pagoda.
What did he want?"
The princess hesitated.
"You're not going to be happy about this," she said.
"But he freed the purple spirit you had captured."
The monster looked angry. "How dare he—"
"The monkey did something else too," said the princess.
"What did he do?" asked the monster.
There was a flash of light.
Suddenly Wukong stood before the monster.
The monkey smiled.
"I freed the princess too!"