"Wukong is right," said Bajie.
"We should all go home and forget about reaching the Western Paradise.
I'll return to my cave and take a nice long nap."
Bajie started to walk away.
[g@Wujing grabbed him.
"Are you crazy?"@g]
[g@He looked at Wukong.
"We can't go home!"@g]
"I know that," said the monkey.
[g@"I wasn't serious about going home.
But I'm angry with Master.@g]
[g@How many times have I warned him about demons?
He never believes me!@g]
If he had listened to me earlier, he wouldn't have been kidnapped."
Wukong sighed. "We need to figure out where the demon took him.
I'll summon a local spirit."
The monkey closed his eyes and muttered some words.
A soft breeze blew, and then a spirit appeared.
[g@"Hello, Sun Wukong," said the spirit.
"I am the spirit of this mountain."@g]
"Our master was kidnapped by a demon," said Wukong.
"We think the demon lives near here, but we don't know where."
[g@"Oh dear," said the spirit.
He looked nervous.@g]
"Your master was probably kidnapped by Red Boy, a very nasty demon.
His cave is near the peak of that mountain."
The spirit pointed to a nearby mountain.
"You shouldn't go there though," the spirit continued.
"Red Boy is very powerful.
His father is the Bull Demon King, one of the most horrible demons ever."
A smile spread across Wukong's face, and he began to laugh.
"That is good news!"
Everyone looked at the monkey in surprise.
"Why is that good news?" asked Wujing.
"The Bull Demon King is an old friend of mine!" said Wukong.
"Before I caused trouble in Heaven, I was friends [n@with a group of demon kings.
The Bull Demon King was one of them.
When I tell Red Boy who I am, he'll release the Tang Monk right away!"
The three travelers said good-bye to the spirit and headed up the mountain.
[g@They came to a cave near the peak.
The door was closed.@g]
[g@Wukong knocked. "Open up, Red Boy.
I need to speak with you!"@g]
The door flew open, and Red Boy stepped out.
[g@"Who are you?" demanded Red Boy.
"What do you want?"@g]
"You kidnapped our master, the Tang Monk," said the monkey.
"Please return him to us."
Red Boy snorted. "I'm not going to return the Tang Monk to you.
I'm going to eat him and live forever.
Now go away before I get very angry!"
Wukong laughed. "My dear boy, you don't realize whom you're talking to.
[g@I am Sun Wukong—the Monkey King.
Your father and I are old friends."@g]
"I don't care who you are!" said Red Boy.
"Now all of you, get off my mountain!"
Wukong shook his head, pretending to be disappointed.
"I was hoping we could solve this problem nicely."
He removed the iron bar from his ear.
Red Boy laughed. "Do you think I'm scared of your little weapon?"
"This iron bar is a treasure from Heaven," said Wukong.
"It was used to measure the oceans and rivers.
It is very powerful and can do whatever I tell it to do."
The monkey puffed out his chest.
"Now return the Tang Monk at once, or I'll destroy your entire mountain!"
[g@"I also have a powerful weapon," said Red Boy.
"I'll show it to you."@g]
The demon punched himself in the nose.
Smoke poured from his nostrils, and fire shot from his mouth.
A moment later flames covered the entire mountainside!