Lady Whitebone sat by the road and sniffed the air again.
"The Tang Monk has some powerful companions," she said.
"I need a disguise."
Bajie dropped the bags.
"I'm tired and hungry.
Let's stop for lunch."
Using his magic sight, Wukong saw a peach orchard thousands of miles away.
"I'll be back in a minute," he said.
Soon after the monkey had left, a young woman came down the road.
She held out a bowl.
"Are you the Tang Monk?" she asked.
"I have food for you."
Bajie reached for the bowl. "Thank you!"
"Don't eat that!" Wukong was flying fast, back to the group.
He dropped all the peaches and pulled out his iron bar.
Wham! He struck at the young woman.
But before he hit her, she disappeared.
"Why did you do that?" cried the Tang Monk.
"You're a human, Master," said Wukong.
"You couldn't see that the woman was really a spirit who wanted to harm you.
Unfortunately she got away."
"Why are you so cruel?" asked the monk.
"She was giving us food."
"It's not food," said the monkey.
"See?" He held up the bowl, which was filled with worms.
"Don't believe Wukong," said Bajie.
"He used magic to turn the food into worms."
The pig looked at the ground where the woman had been and shook his head.
"Wukong hit her so hard, there isn't anything left of her."
"That's ridiculous," said Wukong. "I—ahh!"
The monkey rolled on the ground as the Tang Monk recited the Tight Headband spell.
Bajie laughed. "I didn't know you could do that, Master."
Just then an old woman came down the road.
The monk stopped reciting the spell, and Wukong stood up.
"I'm looking for my daughter," said the woman.
"She was bringing food to the Tang Monk."
"Oh no," said the Tang Monk.
Bajie stepped forward.
"You should ask this monkey what happened to your daughter."
Wukong looked at the old woman closely for a moment.
Then he took out his iron bar and swung.
But again he missed.
"She got away again!" cried Wukong.
"He killed another innocent person!" cried the pig.
"Master, recite the spell!"
The Tang Monk recited the spell again.
Wukong fell to the ground in pain.
"Please stop!" cried the monkey.
The Tang Monk stopped.
"Don't hurt any more people," he said.
"If you do, I'll recite the spell until your head explodes."
Just then an old man came down the road.
"I'm looking for my wife and daughter," he said.
"That's the evil spirit woman again," thought Wukong.
"If I don't destroy her, she'll harm the Tang Monk.
But if I do hurt her, the monk will make my head explode."
Wukong sighed. "I must protect the Tang Monk, no matter what," he thought.
Wukong whipped out his iron bar and swung.
There was a puff of smoke.
When the smoke cleared, a skeleton lay on the ground.
"I got her!" cried Wukong.
"See? She was an evil skeleton spirit!"
The Tang Monk frowned.
"Recite the spell again," Bajie said to the monk.
"I want you to leave, Wukong," said the Tang Monk.
"Master," said the monkey. "I just saved your life."
"I don't believe you," said the monk.
"Now leave or I'll recite the spell again."
Wukong became angry.
"If you really want me to leave, I'll leave.
But don't come looking for me when you need help!"
He leaped into the air and vanished.