The demon eyed the smiling boy suspiciously.
"Aren't you scared of me?" asked the demon.
"No," said the boy. "Should I be?"
"Well, yes," said the demon. "I plan to eat you.
Doesn't that sound terrible?"
The boy shrugged. "Not really."
The demon hesitated for a moment and then moved closer.
Suddenly the boy changed into Wukong.
The monkey pulled out his iron bar and swung.
The demon jumped back, and Wukong missed.
"Who are you?" demanded the demon.
"I am Sun Wukong," said the monkey.
"And you should be ashamed of yourself!
What kind of monster eats children?"
"Sun Wukong?" said the demon.
[g@"I thought you were trapped under a mountain.
What are you doing here?"@g]
"My punishment is over," said the monkey.
"I am traveling to the Western Paradise with the Tang Monk."
[g@The demon's eyes lit up.
"The Tang Monk!"@g]
[g@Wukong lunged.
The demon spun around and disappeared.@g]
The monkey returned to Chen's home and told everyone what had happened.
"Because of you, I still have my son," said Chen. "Thank you."
"You're welcome," said Wukong.
"But I believe the demon now wants to capture the Tang Monk.
So in the morning we must find a boat and leave."
Meanwhile the demon was deep under the water.
"I must capture the Tang Monk and eat him," he said to himself.
[g@"It won't be easy with that monkey around.
I'll need some magic."@g]
[g@Late that night a cold wind blew.
A snowflake drifted to the ground.@g]
Then another one fell, and another.
[g@Bajie couldn't sleep.
"It's freezing in here," he said to himself.@g]
[g@He looked at Wukong and Wujing.
Both of them were sleeping soundly.@g]
"Those two look very comfortable," said the pig.
"Their blankets must be warmer than mine."
In the morning Wukong woke up, shivering.
"Th-that was a t-terrible night's sleep," he said to himself.
[g@"I was so cold!"
He looked down at his body.@g]
[g@"No wonder I was cold!
What happened to my blanket?"@g]
Wujing woke up.
[g@"Why is it so cold in—ah-choo!—in here?
Where did my blanket go?"@g]
[g@They looked at Bajie.
The pig was tucked cozily under three blankets.@g]
Even his head was covered.
[g@Wukong gave him a kick.
"Wake up, thief!"@g]
Bajie rolled over, giggling under the blankets.
Wujing frowned. "You stole our—ah-choo!"
[g@Wukong scratched his head.
"Why is it so cold anyway? It's spring."@g]
[g@He looked out the window and gasped.
"It snowed last night!"@g]
They woke the Tang Monk and Chen, and everyone went outside.
A thick blanket of snow covered the entire village.
"It would be dangerous to cross the river in this weather," said Chen.
"You should stay here until the snow melts."
[g@A villager ran over.
"The river is frozen solid!" he said.@g]
[g@"That's wonderful news!"
The Tang Monk smiled.@g]
"Maybe we can walk across it."
The travelers thanked Chen and said good-bye.
Soon they were standing at the edge of the frozen river.
"I wonder if it's safe to walk on," said Wujing.
"I'll test it with my rake," said Bajie.
The pig walked onto the ice and raised his rake.
[i@Slam!@i] He brought the rake down hard, but the ice didn't crack.
"It's solid," he said.
The travelers stepped onto the ice and started walking.
After a few hours, the riverbank was no longer in sight.
Suddenly there was a rumbling sound, and the ice shook.
"What caused that?" asked the monk.
"I don't know," said Wukong, "But we should be—"
[i@Crack!@i] Underneath them, the ice split wide open!