Wukong and his companions walked on the mountain road.
The monkey watched carefully for the monster and demons.
Suddenly a demon charged toward the group.
"Stay here, everyone!" shouted Bajie.
"I'll fight this demon!"
The pig swung his rake.
The demon stepped off the road and headed down the slope of the mountain.
Bajie raced after the demon and was soon out of sight.
Wukong heard grunts and clashing weapons.
But he couldn't see the fight.
A moment later the demon climbed back onto the road.
"Stay here, Wujing!" shouted Wukong.
"Protect the Tang Monk!"
The monkey charged toward the demon.
Clang! Their weapons clashed.
Wukong fought with all his strength.
Again the demon left the road and headed down the mountain.
Wukong chased him.
The monkey and the demon disappeared down the slope of the mountain.
"Do you think Wukong can defeat that demon?" asked the Tang Monk nervously.
"Definitely," said Wujing.
"I wonder what happened to Bajie though.
I hope he's okay."
Suddenly the demon was back.
Wujing was shocked.
"How did you get past Wukong?"
Without waiting for an answer, Wujing raised his spear and attacked the demon.
The two fought, kicking up dust and rocks.
Wujing struck the demon across the legs.
The demon tumbled down the mountainside.
Wujing ran after him.
The Tang Monk stood in the road.
For a moment everything was quiet.
Then he heard footsteps behind him.
The monk turned around and gasped.
A huge, fat monster was smiling wickedly at him.
When Wukong returned to the road, he found Bajie alone.
The pig looked upset.
"Where are Master and Wujing?" asked the monkey.
Bajie scratched his head.
"I don't know.
I defeated that demon and then came back here.
Everyone was gone."
"You didn't defeat the demon," said Wukong.
"He got past you.
He came back here, and I had to fight him."
"What!" shouted Bajie. "You're crazy!
I was fighting with the demon until just a few moments ago!"
Wukong scoffed.
"Do you really expect me to believe that?
I was just fighting with the demon!"
Wujing returned to the road, annoyed.
"How did that demon get past you two?
He wasn't that powerful."
Wukong was confused.
"The demon didn't get past me.
I was fighting with him until just a moment ago."
"That's impossible," said Wujing.
"After you chased him down the slope, he returned and—
Where's Master?"
Wukong made a fist.
"How could we be so stupid?
There wasn't just one demon.
There were three!
They lured us away, one by one.
Then another demon—probably that fat monster—grabbed Master while we were gone."
Bajie fumed. "You're right!"
"That monster must have a cave nearby," said Wujing.
"Let's find it."
The three companions searched the mountain.
They soon found a cave.
Its door was shut.
"Do you think this is the monster's cave?" asked Wujing.
"We'll find out," said Bajie.
He raised his rake and knocked a hole in the door.
Then he shouted into the hole, "Release the Tang Monk!"
A demon inside the cave shrieked and ran into a kitchen.
The monster was grinding spices with a mortar and pestle.
"That pig is here!" cried the demon.
The monster kept grinding.
"Who cares? I'm only afraid of Wukong."
"I'm here too!" shouted Wukong through the hole.
The monster dropped the mortar and pestle. "Uh-oh."
He thought for a moment.
Then he cleared his throat and shouted, "You're too late!
We already ate the Tang Monk!"