The man walked into the Tang Monk's room.
"Wh-who are you?" asked the Tang Monk nervously.
"I'm king of the Black Rooster Kingdom," said the man.
"My kingdom suffered a horrible drought five years ago.
Crops wouldn't grow, and my people were starving.
One day a Daoist arrived in the kingdom.
He said he had great powers and could pray for rain."
"Did the Daoist's prayers bring rain?" asked the Tang Monk.
[g@The king nodded.
"It rained for days, and our crops began to grow."@g]
[g@"Wonderful!" said the Tang Monk with a smile.
But then his smile faded.@g]
"I'm confused. Why do you need my help?"
The king took a deep breath.
"After the Daoist brought the rain, we became close friends.
One day we were walking when I noticed a strange light coming from my well.
[g@I went to the well and looked in.
Suddenly I felt someone push me in.@g]
[g@It was the Daoist!
He had made the light with magic so he could trick me.@g]
I fell deep into the water, and he sealed the well shut."
Tears came to the king's eyes.
[g@"My body is still down there.
I'm just a . . . ghost."@g]
"That's horrible!" said the Tang Monk.
"Your guards punished the Daoist, right?"
The king shook his head.
"The Daoist made himself look like me, and [n@now everyone thinks he's the real king."
[g@The king paused.
"I've been in the Land of Darkness ever since.@g]
[g@Tonight a spirit brought me to see you.
He said you can help me."@g]
[g@"How can I help you?" asked the Tang Monk.
"I'm just a monk."@g]
"Yes, but you're traveling with Sun Wukong," said the king.
[g@"Sun Wukong is very powerful.
He can destroy the Daoist!"@g]
The Tang Monk hesitated.
"Wukong can't charge into the palace and attack the Daoist.
People will think the monkey is evil, attacking a king for no reason."
"My son, the prince, can bring all of you into the palace," said the king.
"Then Sun Wukong can fight the Daoist in private."
"Where can we find the prince?" asked the monk.
"He will be out hunting tomorrow," said the king.
"Tell him everything I told you."
"But he won't believe us," said the monk.
"He thinks that Daoist is his father."
[g@"Show him this."
The king held up a jade coin.@g]
"This is the one royal treasure I still have.
When my son sees it, he'll know you're telling the truth."
Suddenly the king looked at the door.
[g@"The spirit is calling me.
I must go."
The king vanished.@g]
The Tang Monk called to his companions, who rushed into the room.
The monk told them everything that the king had said.
"He showed me a jade coin," said the monk.
[g@He looked around.
"I don't know where it is now though."@g]
"It was just a dream," said Wukong.
"No, it wasn't a dream," said the monk, still looking around.
[g@He went outside, and the others followed.
"There it is!"@g]
A jade coin lay on the ground by the door.
The next morning the prince went out hunting.
[g@He saw a white rabbit and shot an arrow.
He missed and the rabbit ran.@g]
The prince chased the rabbit as it ran into a monastery.
Inside, the prince saw a monk, a pig, and a purple spirit.
Then the rabbit turned into a monkey.
"What's going on here?" cried the prince.
The monk stepped forward.
[g@"Don't be scared, Prince.
We must tell you something."@g]