The man on the road continued to wave a warning.
Trembling with fear, the Tang Monk fell from his horse.
Wujing rushed over to help him stand up.
"I'll be right back," said Wukong.
"I'll ask that man what sort of danger is up ahead."
The monkey walked toward the man.
Looking closely, Wukong could tell that he was not an ordinary man.
"Hello, Venus," said Wukong with a smile.
[g@The man smiled back.
"Yes, it's me, the spirit of the planet Venus.@g]
I came in disguise to warn you, Wukong.
There are three powerful demons on the mountain up ahead.
The first is a lion demon.
[g@The second is an elephant demon.
And the third is a raptor demon."@g]
[g@The monkey shrugged.
"Thanks for the warning, Venus.@g]
But I'm not worried about three silly demons."
Venus shook his head.
[g@"You should be worried.
The three demons command a demon army."@g]
[g@Wukong rubbed his chin.
"Once again, thank you for the warning.@g]
But even an entire army of demons doesn't worry me."
[g@Venus nodded. "Very well, Wukong. Good luck!"
The spirit vanished.@g]
The monkey walked back to his companions.
[g@"Well?" said Bajie. "What did the man say?
Is there danger up ahead?"@g]
"Are there demons?" asked the Tang Monk, still scared.
"Actually, yes," said Wukong.
[g@"There's an army of demons.
But I'm not worried."@g]
[g@The Tang Monk's jaw dropped.
"How can you not be worried?"@g]
Wukong laughed. "Master, have you forgotten?
I once defeated Heaven's entire army."
Wujing frowned. "Yes, we all know about that, Wukong.
[g@But this is different.
The Tang Monk is with us—we must keep him safe."@g]
Bajie nodded. "Yes, and I'd like to be safe too."
[g@Wukong sighed. "You're right.
We can't let the demons harm Master."@g]
[g@He gave a sideways glance at Bajie and smirked.
"Or the pig."@g]
Bajie snorted.
"You all wait here," said Wukong.
"I'll check out the mountain to see how big the demon army is."
The monkey flew to the mountain.
Several demons were talking in front of a cave.
They were dressed like military officers.
Wukong spied on them from behind a rock.
"The Tang Monk will be coming over our [n@mountain soon," said a demon general.
"Our leaders want all the troops to watch for him."
"I hope we catch the Tang Monk," said a captain.
"I've heard that anyone who eats him will live forever."
[g@Wukong was furious.
"How dare they plan to eat Master!"@g]
The demons were still talking.
"But who will get to eat the monk?" asked another captain.
"There are thousands of troops in our army."
"We'll all get to eat him," said the general.
"Our leaders promised to share him with the entire army."
The other officers nodded and smiled.
"That was very kind of our leaders," said a captain.
"We must be careful though," warned the general.
"Why?" asked a colonel.
[g@"The monk is just a man.
He can't possibly stop us."@g]
"I've heard that the Tang Monk isn't alone," said the general.
"Sun Wukong is with him."
Everyone grew quiet.
"He's the spirit who defeated Heaven's entire army," whispered a captain.
[g@Another captain nodded.
"He is quite powerful."@g]
Wukong beamed proudly when he heard that.
"Don't worry about Sun Wukong," said the general.
"Just tell the troops to watch for the Tang Monk."
"Yes, General," said the colonel.
"I have an idea," thought Wukong.
The monkey made himself look like a demon general.
Then he stepped out from behind the rock and hurried over to the officers.
"I have good news!" shouted Wukong.
"The Tang Monk is heading toward our mountain!"